Krish Naik: Hello everyone, am I audible? Please let me know in the chats.
Krish Naik: Everyone, please, to type.
Krish Naik: Momo this morning can't hear you, please have a check, or those are confirming.
Krish Naik: Alright, okay, we can here. Fine, yes.
Krish Naik: So, today's discussion, so we will continue our chunking, so I think two chunkers were left.
Krish Naik: So, today we will continue our discussion.
Krish Naik: Alright, so let me start… Sharing my screen…
Krish Naik: No, no, no, no, nothing. Today, nothing, okay? So, I'll be talking about today's agenda, don't worry.
Krish Naik: Alright, where is my zoom window?
Krish Naik: This is desktop tool.
Krish Naik: Nay is asking, can we have a short class today? See, something. Yes, the repo will be the same, some minor code changes that I have done, but I've not pushed yet. I will let you know.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, let me open this one, okay? So…
Krish Naik: Let me just change what are the things that previously we have gone, so…
Krish Naik: The same thing, even today, little bit of Llama Index we'll be discussing today, because in Llama Index, I feel there are more retrievers as compared to Langchain, so those examples also I have taken. Okay, so this part, chunking will also continue.
Krish Naik: Okay, and let's see whether we can start hybrid search or not, because I have taken more examples on the Lama Intex side, because I feel those are much more powerful, how to combine multiple retrievers. Okay, so I thought about that's a differentiating factor from LanChain.
Krish Naik: So, let's a little bit talk about tackles.
Krish Naik: Ariane, I want to ask a code chunker, is there any library particularly used for chunking the code data? You can create your manual logic for code chunking based on the programming language you select.
Krish Naik: Or you can use, because,
Krish Naik: directly for a few language supports are available directly in Nangchen, as well in Lama Index also, but not every programming language.
Krish Naik: Okay?
Krish Naik: I am in low voice, I don't think so just yet.
Krish Naik: So, the chunking part we will continue, and then we will look into… so first…
Krish Naik: Let me just change this part.
Krish Naik: Here to here.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: And probably with, before hybrid search, we start, we need to understand
Krish Naik: What is R spectre and dense vector? So, probably that particular topic, is, directly implementing our hybrid search. We need to understand the theoretical part, and how the… both searches are combined together. Okay, and then we will start with the implementations.
Krish Naik: So, let's start. I think you guys already have the notebook, the same continuation of the chonky notebook that we'll be doing today.
Krish Naik: No. Why, Rajat will be doing it in JavaScript?
Krish Naik: our entire AI stack will be purely based on Python.
Krish Naik: Any suggestions on Fort Wheels Shanki?
Krish Naik: Generally, I work with codebases a lot, so in codebases, whenever you are working, you have to search for different type of file extensions.
Krish Naik: Probably you need to parse Jupyter notebooks.mdx files, documentation files in email. So, really, a long list of files that in most repos that you'll be looking into, and based on that.
Krish Naik: A multi-parsing logic with a multi-chunking logic that you need.
Krish Naik: Both need to be combined.
Krish Naik: If he said, distally can't hear you properly, please, guys, do confirm that, I am audible or not.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: audio is good. Let's continue then.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, let me just pull up, I think.
Krish Naik: Our late chunker that we have.
Krish Naik: Okay, so lead chunking is done. Few people have already shared me the meal. I will go through the meal of your custom implementations, and then I think, tomorrow I will reply back. I think Subhas has shared that.
Krish Naik: Yes, Llama Index, a little bit more, I will cover. I feel that the idea is to differentiate with landing, and I feel that Llama Index is much more powerful, so thought about including more things.
Krish Naik: Neural chunk. Alright, fine.
Krish Naik: So two chunkers are left, so let's, go through the documentation of Chonky once.
Krish Naik: I think we have the niggled Chanka, so let me get it.
Krish Naik: So, according to the documentation, so, delete and neural.
Krish Naik: Okay, and finally, the slumber chunker that we have, which is the agent tick chunker.
Krish Naik: Okay, so, first of all, we'll be talking about, the neural Junker implementation.
Krish Naik: And in the neural chunker, I think a few changes I have done, so simply
Krish Naik: Because here, if you try to pass the entire, thing in one shot, you might get some errors. So, few things that I have changed.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, let's go through the documentation.
Krish Naik: Once, so, splitting text using a fine-tuned birth model to detect semantic shifts.
Krish Naik: Now, this is very, very important. So, what do you mean by semantic shifts?
Krish Naik: Anyone?
Krish Naik: Where the context changes.
Krish Naik: It means, generally, we can say that, if you think in chunk respect, okay, with the respective of chunks, I can say that every chunk might have a different semantic meaning.
Krish Naik: Okay, it means that the context will change. If the semantic changes, the idea is to detect those changes, and based on that, you will be, taking the advantage of junk.
Krish Naik: Like, different subjects in a text, correct?
Krish Naik: Okay? Or probably in a complex document, you might have different type of context. So, here, we'll be using a BERT-based model.
Krish Naik: Okay? I think everybody knows about BERT.
Krish Naik: A very common code transformer-based model.
Krish Naik: Now, just be sure you have this installed in your system, the chonky neural part. Okay, and then this is a simple implementation.
Krish Naik: Okay, so now, a very similar one that I have taken. Now, there are a few things, that you need to take care of. In bird-based models, you have positional encoders.
Krish Naik: Yes?
Krish Naik: How many of you know about positional encoders in BERT? Otherwise, please go through that, because right now I'm not teaching you BERT. No.
Krish Naik: Positional inputers, guys?
Krish Naik: Anybody knows about, like, positional encoding?
Krish Naik: Okay, few people know. Otherwise, please have a look into that, because BERT is purely, like, when we teach NLP, then only we discuss that. Right now, I'm not teaching NLP. Okay, so there are positional encoders, and most BERT models have that 512 limit, hard-coded limit. So, if you try to cross that limit, you might get an error.
Krish Naik: So the model cannot process text more than 512 tokens. So, in that case, you have to perform a truncate operation. Okay, and based on that, I have done the change.
Krish Naik: Now, in your notebook.
Krish Naik: I think this is the one. Let me just increase the font so that it should be visible for everyone.
Krish Naik: Now, here I've, picked up the BERT model.
Krish Naik: For tokenization operation. Okay, and the minimum characters per length, 512, that I have defined here. Now, as you can see here, like, the chunk.
Krish Naik: the research paper. Okay, from there, we are picking up the initial 2,000 characters, and that we are passing it to the neural chunk.
Krish Naik: Okay, so just be sure, in your cell also, you have the same piece of code.
Krish Naik: Because I feel that this line of sample text might not be there in your case. Please have it checked, and please do confirm me in the chat.
Krish Naik: Because, I think, in GitHub, just wait.
Krish Naik: Because this is a change, I have done it year study only, so please check. It's not there, no? Please, do that change from the set.
Krish Naik: Mmm, I think this is the notebook, just wait.
Krish Naik: Because one line, otherwise you might get an error with respect to shaping operation.
Krish Naik: Hmm… semantically Chunko.
Krish Naik: Okay, alright, yes, I was getting this error, even, this,
Krish Naik: Shaping error was there, because of that truncate. So I think this code will be there. Just add that part.
Krish Naik: Where you read.
Krish Naik: So, the minimum characters, okay? So, just add this line. I'm sharing this line in the chat.
Krish Naik: Okay. And pass the sample text here.
Krish Naik: Okay, rather than the direct research paper.
Krish Naik: Which has got the same error, yes. The error was due to positional encoding only in BERT, okay? So I'm sharing it in the chat. Everybody, please take that, and just be sure you are passing the text.
Krish Naik: The idea is not to pass that entire thing in one shot.
Krish Naik: And when you look into the error, so probably when, if anybody has executed and got the error, so always try to understand what is the meaning of the error. It's telling that the size of the tensor of a 2801 must match the size of a tensor of a 512 with a non-singleton dimension one.
Krish Naik: So, like, what is the meaning, in simple terms? So, there is a tensor A. The tensor A is having the dimension of 2801. So, that is our actual content, the research paper content that we are passing.
Krish Naik: Okay, but the tensor B, okay, where we are expecting 512, that is the max sequence length, so you cannot surpass that.
Krish Naik: And this generally comes for, positional encodings, which is pretty much hard-coded in most of the BERT models.
Krish Naik: That's why you are getting there. So the idea is to truncate it.
Krish Naik: Okay, please make the change, and please do the confirmation. Because this is a single line change, I think everybody can do it.
Krish Naik: Yes, guys, please confirm in the chat.
Krish Naik: JB is telling this is not truncating it. Yes, the idea is to, make it less than 512, that was the idea.
Krish Naik: Because the model cannot process longer than 215 tokens at one shot.
Krish Naik: So we are trying to feed close to 2801 tokens, so that's why you are getting that particular error.
Krish Naik: And generally, this is for, majorly, like, more than 90% of the board models, you might get it.
Krish Naik: Okay, so everybody please provide the confirmation that after performing, after truncating the input.
Krish Naik: The cell is working correctly.
Krish Naik: DLL initialization, so have a checker widget. So, I'm not sure. If something is not available with respect to C++ in your system, then you might get.
Krish Naik: How many of you are getting a DLL initialization error?
Krish Naik: the dynamic link library, the DLN, because some C++ dependencies might not be there.
Krish Naik: Anybody getting?
Krish Naik: If you are getting, it means that you might not have, and probably you need to install Visual Studio C++ build tools. You have to check, or you need to update that.
Krish Naik: Now, value error, error initializing the model using a device map, TP plan.
Krish Naik: So, generally, see, in the documentation, let's go through the documentation.
Krish Naik: So, the device map, you can make it CPU manually.
Krish Naik: Okay, if you feel the device map is not getting supported, please have a check, whoever wants to pass this parameter. Okay, please go through the dots, because in this implementation, I know this is transformer-based implementation, so you might get more errors.
Krish Naik: As compared to the other implementations till now, that we have gone through.
Krish Naik: Because here, what we are trying to perform, we are actually trying to look for a semantic change, okay, within our document.
Krish Naik: whoever is getting there, please try to check, because in my case, I have not passed that, but you can pass the device map manually.
Krish Naik: And exactly, what is happening. So, let's try to understand a little bit of that. Okay, so I will just stop sharing this one. Let's get back to our notes.
Krish Naik: So, where is my iPad screen? Please provide a confirmation that you guys are able to see the iPad.
Krish Naik: Cheers.
Krish Naik: Now here, token classification happens.
Krish Naik: how many of you know that token classification is a very common, like, identifying chunk boundaries, okay? So, let's talk about that.
Krish Naik: Okay, so the same notes I will be using. Okay, I've already shared this note with the team, I think they will upload it. So yesterday, the guy who uploads, he was having birthday, so he was on a holiday, so I think late night he might have done it, but probably the notes will be updated, so don't worry.
Krish Naik: DQ.
Krish Naik: Product.
Krish Naik: Now, this is our neural chunker.
Krish Naik: Now, in this neural chakra, we are using, basically, a BERT-based model for detecting any type of semantic shift.
Krish Naik: The idea is to detect semantic shift.
Krish Naik: Now, how we will detect that semantics? Now, the question comes simply.
Krish Naik: Okay, so we'll be using a BERT-based model.
Krish Naik: a BERT model, For now.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: And how the BERT model will identify the semantic shapes. You have to understand that. So, first of all, it will split the document, okay, into tokens.
Krish Naik: Whatever the document that you are passing, it will be provided into tokens.
Krish Naik: And then from the tokens, you will be doing a token classification.
Krish Naik: This is very, very important. Okay, so, like, generally, birth-based models or GPT-based models both can perform the same task.
Krish Naik: Okay? So, like, they simply can, do the token classification.
Krish Naik: token classification.
Krish Naik: Now, when I'm talking about token classification, so simply, it here, I refer to identifying
Krish Naik: Junk boundaries.
Krish Naik: This is the core purpose, and most BERT-based models will be having a hard limit of 512 tokens, okay?
Krish Naik: Now, anybody has used any variants of both, like distal boat, cool boat, anything like that?
Krish Naik: semantic shift.
Krish Naik: Semantic shift refers to the change in the context within your document.
Krish Naik: Okay? Like, distal birth, cold, but different variants of birds are there. So there, it might change. Sometimes it can be 786 also, 1024, it totally depends upon the variant of the bird. But core birth-based models have a pretty much hard token limit.
Krish Naik: Where 512 is defined. Okay, and due to… this is a positional encoding constraint.
Krish Naik: Whenever you say, why this limit comes, this is purely because of positional encoding.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, like, it's in the architecture, nothing that we can…
Krish Naik: Alright, so… Hi.
Krish Naik: step by step, how they are detecting the shift, okay? So, first of all, the documents get feeded, you will be getting your data points, or basically the tokens, then the token classification take place, through which you will be identifying the chunk boundaries, okay? So, let's up the model. This is the mean flow.
Krish Naik: So she was telling I will use the distal part? None help me. Just check that. Okay, otherwise, by you, I will look into that later.
Krish Naik: Fine. Now, let's get back to our implementation.
Krish Naik: Now, really, like, neural chunkers, Are good, but really very, very slow.
Krish Naik: Now, I think everybody has done the installation, so let's get back to our… Wow.
Krish Naik: notebook.
Krish Naik: Cheers.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, just try to execute. So, here, I'm not taking the entire
Krish Naik: document. I have just done a truncation operation.
Krish Naik: Okay, and based on that, when I try to load it up.
Krish Naik: Okay, so you will see that, right now, based on the chunk, there is a single chunk. Because I've not passed the entire document. Later on, you can truncate it, and through a for loop, you can go through the entire document.
Krish Naik: Okay, now this is only for one chunk that I am showing, because for one chunk, when you look into the distribution, and even if you look into the block spot, okay, so here, one chunk, so…
Krish Naik: For sure, there won't be any type of outlass.
Krish Naik: And every value, if you would look into, this is only one chunk, so all the values are exactly the same.
Krish Naik: Now, the question comes, like, when you have two levels of chunky. Now, this is an implementation on top of neural chunker that I have done.
Krish Naik: It means that I have taken a token chunker first, then on top of that, the neural chunker that I have applied. A two-step process. Okay, so the idea is to pass 512 multiple times because of that. You can change the chunk size or the overlap, it can be increased to bigger numbers.
Krish Naik: But for now, in the first implementation, the idea is to manage that 512 limit. So, that limit, I am managing it through the token chunk. Now, whatever will be the output from the token chunk…
Krish Naik: that, I will pass it to the nibble channel. So in that way, I can always maintain that limit, for semantic chunking.
Krish Naik: Okay, now comes in the next step.
Krish Naik: the neural chunker definition. So, in the previous one, it's simply one piece of text that I have passed, but this time, I'll be passing the full document. So, first of all, the pre-chunker, the fixed chunking window size, through which I am passing my original research paper text. If you remember, it is the same document.
Krish Naik: Now, here, can you see a simple for loop that I have passed?
Krish Naik: On top of our pre-chunks.
Krish Naik: Now, this will take care that every time you are within the safe margin limit of 512.
Krish Naik: Okay, and then only you are passing it in. So, this is a safe strategy whenever you are working with burst-based model for topic detection, or basically for, looking for semantic shifts within your document.
Krish Naik: And then finally, I am just printing out My chums, let's see.
Krish Naik: Alright, yes, I think this code you guys might not have with you, yes, I think 3 people told about this one. This, I will just quickly paste it in, because this is a custom implementation that I have done. Just wait, I will paste it in Notion. I think it will be better, you guys can quickly access it.
Krish Naik: Because… Just wait.
Krish Naik: Okay, let me get motion.
Krish Naik: Okay, so… for here, I will just create a page.
Krish Naik: Game.
Krish Naik: Okay, so here I am pasting the entire code. Please have a look.
Krish Naik: So, directly, like, if I go to, like, view sites…
Krish Naik: I'm just sharing the link in the chart. Please try to open the Notion from here.
Krish Naik: you'll be getting this piece of code, because this minor change that I have done today.
Krish Naik: Okay? Please do copy this.
Krish Naik: When I'm just telling, it won't be able to get the context out of the entire document.
Krish Naik: Mmm… it won't be able to get the context out of the entire document. Why?
Krish Naik: It won't be able to get the context.
Krish Naik: You want me to push? I can do the push also.
Krish Naik: So I think in mining part chalk here, okay.
Krish Naik: That's another huge sunset.
Krish Naik: Okay, even I'm pushing it in GitHub, just have a check.
Krish Naik: Okay, so this also I have updated, so from any web, just try to pull.
Krish Naik: Alright, I've shared the Notion link as well as I think everybody got the code. Please…
Krish Naik: Provide the confirmation, got it.
Krish Naik: I think from Notion, quickly, you can actually get it.
Krish Naik: Now, in this case, so 3 chunks are created directly based on the application. So now, see, can you see here? Now, this is a strategy. I don't know how many of you use two levels of chunking.
Krish Naik: First of all, a token level chunker. On top of that, you have a neural level chunker. Okay, so this is a two-level, just to take care of my safer limits that I have done.
Krish Naik: Otherwise, you can create a custom function where you only handle 512 tokens. In that way, also, you can do, but I thought about direct implementation is already available, so let's pick up the chunky and apply it in our current tool.
Krish Naik: Now, based on that, okay, so every time, the token count is close to 400, in some cases, because right now only 3 chunks, okay, based on those 3 chunks that I have shown you.
Krish Naik: Okay, I… if you really look into the box plot here, so I can see it's… the range is coming close from 360 to 400, and if you really look into the statistics, some of the standard deviation towards the lower side, close to 10% of the mean, so this is good.
Krish Naik: I can say. So, generally, less than 30% is a good metric that you can always take into account.
Krish Naik: And finally, getting the mean and the max. Okay, so the mean and the max, the token difference is close to, like, 76, I can say.
Krish Naik: Not a very big range, if you try to compare it with our previous chunkers that we have really gone through, where the difference was sometimes more than 100. I can say at least better.
Krish Naik: Okay? Now, Swagithika is asking, sir, chunky is used only for chunky? Yes, majorly it's used for chunking. This library is built only for majorly chunking. That's why the name Chonki comes. Swagatika.
Krish Naik: index out of range, I am getting an error even after putting the range. Please have a check, too. Recently I pushed the code again in GitHub, so I think from GitHub, you can access that.
Krish Naik: So, this file, let me just, reload it.
Krish Naik: Because just now I have pushed. Everybody please confirm, is the code that I have shared, it's just one line, two lines of update. Is it working in your system or not?
Krish Naik: Guy got it. Please let me know, guys. Nobody has told it's working.
Krish Naik: Somebody is telling, like, index out of range. I don't think you'll be getting an index out of range. Pramesh, thanks. Pramesh has confirmed that it's working. Everybody, please try it out.
Krish Naik: Quickly, take one minute and try it out.
Krish Naik: Now,
Krish Naik: When… okay, now this is a nice question, I think. Somebody asked in the chat. Okay, Pramesh is asking, in the case of neural chunking, when you are dividing the document into smaller chunks, how does, it makes sure it is not losing the context?
Krish Naik: So generally, in the token chunker, you pass this chunk size and chunk overlap. Through chunk overlap, we know the preservation of the context at mount lists that take place from each.
Krish Naik: It's not only about picking up. There, the chunk size and the chunk overlap concept comes from Ish.
Krish Naik: So, please have a look into the code.
Krish Naik: Shamek Shah is also telling index out of range. Please try to restart the notebook, okay? That can be another reason. Please try to restart after making the changes. Everybody.
Krish Naik: Okay, because I don't think a restart is required, but in that case, if you're getting an error, please do a restart.
Krish Naik: If we run from start, it works. Abhijit has confirmed that. Thanks, Abhijit.
Krish Naik: Sanket, it worked.
Krish Naik: device set to CPU is also coming along with index, because I know the index, really, like, the higher index value is 2801.
Krish Naik: And initially, I'm picking up only 2,000 characters, so I know those are tokens, so it has to be less than that. You won't be getting, so please have a check.
Krish Naik: No E23178 specifically in your case only. Others, not.
Krish Naik: Right now, I have not set a random seed. Because of that, the results from the birth, it can differ by June.
Krish Naik: Mitesh is also telling index error.
Krish Naik: Really, how you guys will get the indexer, that only I'm thinking.
Krish Naik: Because I am picking up only 2,000 characters. This is characters, these are not tokens, and the number of tokens that I have in the document is 2801. So, for sure, it has to be less. Because this is a simple logical concept.
Krish Naik: So, whoever it is getting, please have a check.
Krish Naik: The chonky version is 1.5.0, or you can use 1.5.1.
Krish Naik: Working fine with no errors.
Krish Naik: working fine. Really, guys, like, should…
Krish Naik: Have a check, or later on, I will look into what is the issue.
Krish Naik: Okay, so probably try a restart of the notebook, and then…
Krish Naik: Because this is a BERT-based implementation, so I know few people might get an inner.
Krish Naik: See, I've already shared the code, Sanket, so I hope that others are using the same one. If you pass the research paper text, you will get that error.
Krish Naik: appreciate. Please do that.
Krish Naik: Alright, now let's get back, to the Zoom book.
Krish Naik: The gods,
Krish Naik: Because there are only two cells that you have, so I think…
Krish Naik: It should work for everyone if it's working in my system.
Krish Naik: Otherwise, I will look into the issue later on, okay?
Krish Naik: All right. Now, the neural chunker implementation that we have done.
Krish Naik: No, the next one after the neural chunker… okay. Now, the question comes, in neural chunking.
Krish Naik: actually, BERT is able to detect
Krish Naik: the semantic changes within your document. How many of you think that BERT is able to do that? You have to understand that.
Krish Naik: Because, according to theory, it should detect, but practically, with respect to the implementations.
Krish Naik: Anybody else worked with Bert for any type of problem? Like, probably, like, fill in the blanks, sequencing problem?
Krish Naik: Because generally, BERT is used whenever you have a masking-based, problem in NLP.
Krish Naik: Takesh is asking when to use BERT. Please go and cover the NLP fundamental status.
Krish Naik: It can be used for a lot of tasks, token classification.
Krish Naik: Okay, even for in-ear and washtag-based tasks also, you can use both.
Krish Naik: Alright, now, I hope it is working in few systems it's working, otherwise I will look into the issue exactly why it's not working.
Krish Naik: Now, finally, we have a slumber chunker. Okay, now, whenever… because now, let's look into slumber chunker, because this is an agentic chunker, an LLM-powered agent. It means that it will use an LLM to intelligently determine chunk boundaries.
Krish Naik: But, for LLM-based, chunking strategies, whenever we are asking any LLM,
Krish Naik: So, what… how the LLM works, okay? So, let's focus on that. So, let's, first of all, go through the documentation, how they have defined it, and then I will be talking about a few concepts out there with respect to propositions. So, exactly what is a proposition, and how an LLM tries to find the proposition.
Krish Naik: Now, in our samba Chanker.
Krish Naik: Okay, so this is an agentic part, the latest one. Okay, and just be sure you have Genie installed, the chonky Genie version with a pip.
Krish Naik: Okay, and here, you will be integrating it with APIs. It can be Gemini, it can be OpenAIM. So you have to select whichever, I can say, like, LLM model that you want to pick up.
Krish Naik: So, it's telling that, the magic behind the Slumber Junker is a genie. Chunker's new interface for integrating generative models and APIs. So, Jenny allows Slumber Chunker to intelligently analyze text structure.
Krish Naik: Identify optimal split points, and even summarize and rephrase the content for best possible junk quality.
Krish Naik: Okay, now it's telling that everything it's doing, it means analyzing the text structure, identifying optimal split points, and even summarize or rephrase the content for the best possible chunk quality.
Krish Naik: But, let's try to go in detail, because this is very high level. First of all, you have to understand what is, this, I can say, optimal split points or, data points that the LLM tries to analyze. Okay, so let me just get to my notes.
Krish Naik: Now, this concept is really, I feel, interesting also. Like, somehow.
Krish Naik: the LLM strives to detect So, now the cushion comes.
Krish Naik: The… in LLM-based chunking, exactly.
Krish Naik: how it tries to determine whether it is a semantic unit or not, okay? With respect to semantic units, when I am referring,
Krish Naik: I refer to a proposition.
Krish Naik: So, let's cover this one. Here, I will say, and… Agent tick.
Krish Naik: Okay. LLM?
Krish Naik: chunking approach.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, in LLM-based chunking, okay, the idea is to find a semantic unit.
Krish Naik: semantic unit.
Krish Naik: Now, this semantic unit is referred to as proposition.
Krish Naik: No, nobody actually talks about propositions a lot, because propositions refers to a semantic unit of meaning.
Krish Naik: Okay, it can be… you can think about, a small part of a paragraph, okay, or more meaningful than fixed time charts. Okay, somewhere more meaningful.
Krish Naik: Then, fix size chunks.
Krish Naik: fixed.
Krish Naik: size, Chunks.
Krish Naik: Okay, so whenever you are working with a token-based chunker, so they have a fixed size chunking, so it really doesn't matter whether it's capturing a semantic meaning or not. So, by default, it will try to perform a chunk operation. So, the idea is how to capture that semantic unit.
Krish Naik: Okay, so this proposition refers to…
Krish Naik: An atomic, okay, or a self-content, factual, or a logical statement.
Krish Naik: an atomic…
Krish Naik: Self-contained.
Krish Naik: It can be a fact, so that's why I'm writing a factual.
Krish Naik: Or a logical statement.
Krish Naik: Okay. It means that the chunk can be small also, so that's why I'm referring to the word atomic. It's not necessary every time your chunk will be very, very big.
Krish Naik: Okay? Now, the concept of proposition has been very, very… it's a very, very old concept, which comes from classical NLP, simply. Okay, so where you work with linguistics and knowledge representation. I think the study of NLP before that, you have NLE, your natural language understanding.
Krish Naik: This is nothing a new concept.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: In the study of…
Krish Naik: NLU, natural, your natural language understanding, you have this concept of proposition. Now, the same way. So, recently in RAT, now, the idea came that, okay, why not use ALMs, specifically, to perform a chunk
Krish Naik: operation. Now, when you think of a proposition, always think it, that it can be one fact, it can be one claim, or some type of rule.
Krish Naik: Okay, it means that that will be having some type of major effect on top of the content that you are trying to process.
Krish Naik: Now, Vijita's asking why Slumber Chankar is used in agents as compared to others. Why slumber chunker is used in agents? It's not agents, it's actually the LLMs. You make the LLM call through an agent. Agent can be a function for now, which is created in that.
Krish Naik: So, actually, we are using an LLM. It's not agent, I'm not using any Langraph or any such other agentic framework. It's purely, I am using an LLM call through an agent.
Krish Naik: And generally, agent, you can refer it as a function.
Krish Naik: Now, whenever you think of a proposition, you have to think that, fundamentally, it has to be some type of fact, claim, okay, or some type of rule, a very important one, or it can be a major mathematical formula also, it can be. It means that it should have a very high weightage with respect to semantic representation.
Krish Naik: And most of the times, your proposition will be, like, independent.
Krish Naik: Okay, it means that, whenever I'm talking about the concept of independent, it can think about both the context, if you have two different chunks. They will have, like, independent context.
Krish Naik: And that can also be verified.
Krish Naik: And even, like, according to NLP, they can be embeddable also. But we know that any piece of text can be embeddable for now.
Krish Naik: Now, let's take a simple example.
Krish Naik: To understand propositions.
Krish Naik: Nerd stick.
Krish Naik: Now, when you look into a sentence, okay, so right now, I have taken simply, like Paul is, another, I will say.
Krish Naik: Let's take another sentence here. At least two sentences, and based on two sentences, I can create chunks, at least.
Krish Naik: Okay? So here, so I've taken a… for now, you can think about… this is a simple paragraph, okay? And in this particular paragraph, there are simple two sentences that I have taken. Okay. Now, when you look into, propositions.
Krish Naik: So, now, if you actually look into the first one, like, Paul is going to London, okay? Now, do you think that is a fact?
Krish Naik: Or it is a claim, or it is a rule. For now, can I say that it's not a fact for sure? It's just a claim? Yes or no?
Krish Naik: Yes or no, because this is not a universal fact, guys. Okay? Like, every ball goes to London. It's not like that, okay? So it's just a claim that I'm making. Okay, so the idea is, okay, now it will try to capture the relationship in the first page. When I actually try to break it into propositions.
Krish Naik: The first sentence that I have, so let's take this sentence.
Krish Naik: This is as your, I will say sent to 1, because every time I don't want to write the complete sentence, and this is your sent to.
Krish Naik: Okay, so for the first sentence, sent one.
Krish Naik: This is a claim that I have.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, this actually becomes Proposition 1.
Krish Naik: Okay, it means that through an LLM, you will try to find exactly, like, what is a proposition. Now, coming to the second part of the example, where I am telling that Paul loves football.
Krish Naik: Now, again, what is this? This is, again, a claim I can say, because this is not a universal fact.
Krish Naik: Yes. Now, for cent to…
Krish Naik: Again, not click.
Krish Naik: So right now, in this paragraph, how many propositions I have.
Krish Naik: Can I say that each line is a proposition?
Krish Naik: Because these are two different claims, and if you really try to understand, like, this is… Paul is going to London, and Paul loves football. Do you think that they have the same context?
Krish Naik: Because both are totally different claims within a single paragraph.
Krish Naik: Okay?
Krish Naik: So, the idea is, basically, we will try to… we don't try to find, it's actually the LLM which will try to find propositions, okay, within the document that we'll be passing, and based on that, now you have to understand.
Krish Naik: the original document, okay, whichever you are, passing. Okay, so it's, I cannot say that every point of time, as even in the documentation it has stored, it can even perform a rephrase operation.
Krish Naik: Okay, just to make your main context much more compact, this can also happen.
Krish Naik: Okay, so it's not only about your original document. So, let's go through the documentation once again. I will just show you that part. Even in the documentation, they have mentioned about that. So this is our TikTok tool.
Krish Naik: And you see here, it will try to identify optimal split points, and generally, so, how to identify the optimal split points?
Krish Naik: Byte?
Krish Naik: Pro positions. Everybody, please try to understand.
Krish Naik: Okay, so if anybody asks you how to identify the optimal splits within, so you have to look for propositions, and then you can see here, even summarize or rephrase the content for the best possible chunk quality.
Krish Naik: It means you are performing a summarization operation or a refreeze operation on top of your actual data.
Krish Naik: So that's why, really, I'm not a fan of this. Okay, it's just because I feel that I don't want to change my original data.
Krish Naik: Okay, in some cases, if you really feel that, how many of you feel that you should perform a summarize or a rephrase operation on top of your original content? That… is that a correct way?
Krish Naik: Just try to understand, because actually, this is a simple label of data manipulation. I don't think, like, you can keep this data, like Mitesh is telling, for metadata, yes, for metadata, you can do.
Krish Naik: Generally, like, Methesh, for metadata, you can apply some type of summarization or a rephrasing, like, first try to rephrase and then try to perform a summarize on top of the chunk level data, but not directly on top of our actual content.
Krish Naik: But somehow, it might hamper our original, document.
Krish Naik: Okay, so really, that's why I don't always prefer always to go with a chunk, because it always comes with the cost.
Krish Naik: It's very, very slow as compared to other chunking, but again, like, if somebody has a requirement very specifically where they can actually change your main data, and on top of that, if you want to perform a rephrase content.
Krish Naik: So it means that manipulation of the original content. And just think, if it's summarized or rephrases somehow in the wrong way, it means that there will be problems. It means that you have to always use good quality LLMs.
Krish Naik: You cannot actually look for, okay, let's try to go for a cheap solution. Then, somehow, there can be problems with this.
Krish Naik: Now, let's get back and let's try to look into exactly how LLM does it.
Krish Naik: So, the actual flow for pre-procession detection in simple terms. So, first of all, what will happen?
Krish Naik: Hmm… in the major text. All right.
Krish Naik: Now, LLM-based, proposition chunking. Okay, so your LLM… Based.
Krish Naik: That's why I'm using this term, proposition, a lot, so that you guys get used to this. Majorly few places I have seen, otherwise they will directly say an LLM-based charging, but really, behind the scenes, what happens, you have to always understand.
Krish Naik: So, the first flow will be, you will be having some document. Let's take a document for now.
Krish Naik: that document, you will be passing it to the LLM.
Krish Naik: Now, it's the job of the LLM to extract propositions.
Krish Naik: Now, so once these propositions are extracted, so you can think each proposition becomes a check.
Krish Naik: Okay? And once, you have the chunk, you know that in the next step, you can save it in VectorTube.
Krish Naik: Now, this is the actual flow. So, whenever I'm talking about the proposition identification.
Krish Naik: Okay, so it means that everything will be done by the LLM, so really, like, I don't have much to do here.
Krish Naik: Okay, because on top of the data when I'm applying, is it the same or semantic chunking? No, this is not. Here, directly, you are using. Is there any specifications how much percentage of the data it will change? No. Really. It totally depends. See, if I send something to the LLM, do you think that if you pass the document, you have the control?
Krish Naik: Okay, probably, like, you can create a prompt, and in that prompt, you can say that, okay, I can create. So, pretty much a direct custom implementation that you can do. But in Chonky, it's directly passing the data.
Krish Naik: Okay, so if you want that custom-based implementation, then through a prompt, very specifically, you can ask that, okay, now this, you have to identify the propositions, never do rephrasing, never do, in that way, you have to create a personalized prompt. And then you have to pass that prompt to them.
Krish Naik: Okay, so that will be pretty much custom, but in Chonky, that is not there.
Krish Naik: propositions almost like different context, yes. So, different context, so that's why. So, when you were talking about a context, okay, so I was talking about, like, it can be a fact, it can be a claim, it can be a rule.
Krish Naik: Now, the question comes, how to identify a good preposition. So, just remember, they have to be atomic. It means that one idea only.
Krish Naik: So, when I use the term atomic.
Krish Naik: Here, okay. It doesn't mean so very small. Okay, the idea was to refer here.
Krish Naik: Okay, one idea only. That you do need to mix multiple ideas together.
Krish Naik: Okay, and generally, if you have something like pronouns, even then it can sometimes create a problem. So, generally, it's preferred to clean the pronouns most of the times. Like, it should be self-contained also.
Krish Naik: It means that there should not be, like, this, it. The idea is so that it doesn't need to look into your previous text.
Krish Naik: Okay, otherwise it might lose the context. Pretty much declarative, okay? Which can be true or false, in simple terms, if you think it that way.
Krish Naik: And it even should be context complete. It means the subject even with the relation. In that way, multiple things which comes. Now, all these things that I am telling, this comes from classical NLP, what people have been doing back from 2008, really. It's not deep learning NLP.
Krish Naik: Yes, a proposition can have multiple sentences, Salandi.
Krish Naik: But…
Krish Naik: they should be different. So when you are taking multiple sentences, then I can say that, yes, the first sentence is somehow related to the second, then if they are totally different claims, or different rules. So that's why I've taken
Krish Naik: From that semantic unique meaning.
Krish Naik: I hope you got.
Krish Naik: No,
Krish Naik: Traditional chunking, really doesn't look into that. Now, the idea is that the LLM will try to find the propositions for you, and based on that, it will be creating chunks. Okay, like P1, P2, P3. So, generally, you can think about your chunks as… so, for example, if you have your chunk.
Krish Naik: Let's take C1.
Krish Naik: C2, C3, C4, 4 chunks. So, these are actually your first proposition, second, third, and fourth.
Krish Naik: And that…
Krish Naik: Now, whenever we are working with prepositions, it improves the RAG retrieval. Okay, now, this has been improved in, multiple research papers also. Now, when I'm talking with prepositions, now, how? So, first of all, it will help you to increase that retrieval accuracy. Your retrieval accuracy will be increased.
Krish Naik: Okay, so this will be on the higher side. Less hallucinations comes.
Krish Naik: Now, an even better factual grounding also happens.
Krish Naik: Because if you actually try to change the cortex, so…
Krish Naik: Somehow, on top of your original text.
Krish Naik: This also take place.
Krish Naik: And, even we have seen from the implementation that it really works good with hybrid search. Tell them not hybrid search, okay, but it really works very, very good with hybrid search as well as for e-ranking. Okay, so later on I'll be talking about these topics, but always remember, it works better
Krish Naik: with hybrid.
Krish Naik: And a re-ranking also.
Krish Naik: Okay, so…
Krish Naik: Now, in which cases you might use, whenever you have some type of technical docs, research paper, in those cases, it is good. So, for example, if you try to pass some type of novel, in those cases, this particular technique is not good.
Krish Naik: Always remember. Now, there are very specific, like, technical documents, research papers, FAQs, okay, something like a legal document, medical text, in those, type of documents, it really works.
Krish Naik: But if you just try to pass some novel. Okay, where actually, the idea is, not only to capture
Krish Naik: context, okay? Through, like, if you feel that your context is actually spread out in multiple places. In those cases, it's not good.
Krish Naik: Because if you really think about a novel, he, she, in that way, there can be multiple contexts. So, the idea was not to use a lot of pronouns in simple terms.
Krish Naik: first thing that I have told, according to your classical energy.
Krish Naik: So, in those cases, it's not so much good.
Krish Naik: There can be, but at least it has to be towards the lower side.
Krish Naik: Alright, we have gone through the concept of propositions a lot.
Krish Naik: Okay, and right now, it will be requiring an LLM call for share.
Krish Naik: Now, let's get back.
Krish Naik: to our chonky.
Krish Naik: Screens, this is desktop.
Krish Naik: All right, now let's start with our, so here, if you really look into the initialization step, so first of all, this lumber chunker, then from there, we are getting the Gemini journey. So similarly, if you are working with OpenAI, it will be OpenAI journey, in that we have to change that.
Krish Naik: Gemini Jenny 3 ProView, so right now, this is the model that you'll be working with. Then comes the initialization of the chunker, where you'll be passing which LLM that you'll be using. Then, for your tokenizer, what tokenizer that you'll be using, so right now, Character, the other default option.
Krish Naik: Then comes your chunk size, so 124, that I'm passing here. Now, candidate size. Now, this is very important, and try to understand how many tokens Jenny looks for potential splits.
Krish Naik: Okay, it means that, though you are telling that, okay, I have a requirement of chunk size of 10, that is the max limit, but actually how many tokens you want the LLM to see, to find prepositions.
Krish Naik: Now, minimum characters per chunk, even, because in this case, what happens, sometimes you might have, lists. Just think about if you have a single sentence.
Krish Naik: As a proposition.
Krish Naik: Okay, it might have less characters, yes or no.
Krish Naik: Yes or no?
Krish Naik: Because in this condition, you are telling the LLM to find a preposition, and if you think about the single sentence that if it tries to find, okay, in that case, you need to maintain this also.
Krish Naik: Because, at least, if you have 5 characters, really, that doesn't make up a lot of meaning. The idea is to capture more context. So that's why, like, minimum characters per chunk.
Krish Naik: is also available, so that you need to pass. So, generally, it can be at least, so whatever the size of candidate that you are passing, just be sure it is, close to 10-20% of time.
Krish Naik: max size we have provided, so most of the times, it won't reach 1024. That is also one condition. Very less…
Krish Naik: number of times it reaches at least close to this number also. Most of the times, it will be towards the lower side.
Krish Naik: And let's try to print, now, this initialization.
Krish Naik: Yes, 24 characters is really low. But, this candidate size, if you are increasing it to 256, then you can increase this one. So always take a 20% to 30% ratio for your minimum characters based on that.
Krish Naik: Now, these are minimum characters, I'm not telling the chunk size, it can be more than that. In some cases, if a lesser number of characters comes, then that chunk will be ignored, and again, regenerated.
Krish Naik: Allowing, by default, if you really look into it, it's not like that, your entire document will be rephrased. Okay, so let's look into the implementation first of all.
Krish Naik: There's… Alright, so… Where is mine?
Krish Naik: Slumber chunk of, yes.
Krish Naik: Now, the same implementation, only thing, I'm not using Gemini here, I'm using OpenAI.
Krish Naik: Rest, the model selection, going with GPT4.1.
Krish Naik: Now, here, so let's try… I have done the initialization.
Krish Naik: And here, I am passing the research text, so I'm not passing the entire, it takes a lot of time, because this is very, very slow, okay? Because you will be using LNNs.
Krish Naik: It comes with a cost, so the idea is not to spend a lot, so don't pass big documents. If somebody's using some manual, please don't pass a very, very big. So right now, it has come close to…
Krish Naik: 77 splits, and right now the number of chunks is close to 8, as compared to others.
Krish Naik: Okay, so I can say that somehow it is better, and right now, the token count, if you really look into it.
Krish Naik: Total chunks? 8. Now, this is one of the highest number of chunks that has been generated yet. 10 now, in all the other chunking strategies, it has not been generated.
Krish Naik: Now, based on the document, if you really look into… now, this part I know, this is exactly from the research paper it has picked up. So, till now, I won't say there is a rephrasing part. Now, let's try to look into this chunk too, okay, on top of your original one. So, let me just get to my data folder.
Krish Naik: And I think this is the sample one.
Krish Naik: So… Somehow… okay, let me just, copy that thing, and let's try to find it here.
Krish Naik: So, it's telling, we introduce this one.
Krish Naik: And this is from here, let's do a Ctrl-F, let's try to paste it. Okay, now from here, it has picked up one chunk.
Krish Naik: really, like, when I look into the main document, All right.
Krish Naik: Now, on top of this, we introduce a novel hybrid approach that combines the efficiency of token-based chunking with the semantic awareness.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, really, you have to analyze this data, and if you really look into this data.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, this vein. So, now, this has a different context here, because this is based on the technical paper, so one part. In most chunkers, you will feel that, okay, so this can be
Krish Naik: part of the same chunk based on the size decision. But here, it has taken it as a… another chunk.
Krish Naik: Now, let's get back here to our original one, chunk 3. Again, if you look to chunk 3, it has started again from a middle perspective, because the token count, I told you it'll be always less than 1024, so somehow close to 868 at its fee stat.
Krish Naik: Initially, it has some cons, I can say, context with respect to RAG.
Krish Naik: Second one, we introduced. This one, it has much lower counts.
Krish Naik: Now, come to… coming to your chunk 3, this is having close to 855, but let's try to analyze how it has done.
Krish Naik: So, Central, let's again try to find this…
Krish Naik: Thing here, okay? Now, alright, now, simply you can say it has broke. So, generally, it's not capturing this part.
Krish Naik: generally, I know if I use some other chunkers, I can pass it through, like, one introduction. Directly on top of that, it becomes much easier. But here, it's actually broken in between. So somehow, the initial context, I feel that we are losing.
Krish Naik: But if you really think about, this is pretty much an independent one.
Krish Naik: It's not directly dependent on another sentence. Effective RAG implementation, so I can say that, yes, an identification of proposition, and this continues till the number of characters in that phase.
Krish Naik: Okay, so, okay, Hindu is here only.
Krish Naik: Okay, and other 5 chunks are there, that has been taken. Now, if you really look into the data, I don't feel this is always correct.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, based on the result, because when I'm directly giving it to the LLM, my core objective here, if I want a perfect one, somehow I will try to capture through this.
Krish Naik: Okay, at least in this way, starting from the core part.
Krish Naik: Okay, because there can be more, but I feel that
Krish Naik: The number of tokens, it's not very high.
Krish Naik: at least in the first paragraph, if you really look into it. I can keep this thing in a single piece of context, but actually, when you split it.
Krish Naik: Somehow. And this result will be different for everybody. I'm using GPT-4.1. If you change the LLM, in your case, the output can be different.
Krish Naik: Please, anybody working with Gemini, please let me know in the chat.
Krish Naik: Because for me, working with GPA, I think GPT 4.1, I'm getting 8 chunks. Anybody getting different than 8 chunks?
Krish Naik: No, no, this will not work with tables moment.
Krish Naik: Abhiches is getting 9 chunks.
Krish Naik: Okay, Balaji, 9 checks, yes, that's right. That will change if you change the LLM, because the identification of the proposition is totally… happens in that way.
Krish Naik: You got 9 chunks, alright, so…
Krish Naik: This will be different even, like, if you switch to Llama, it can be lesser also.
Krish Naik: If you change the chunk size, if you try to lower the chunk size somehow to 512, then you will have more chance. But, if you try to keep the same uniform, so somehow it will be impactful. So I feel that always working with LLMs, this is not a good solution.
Krish Naik: Though… okay, now most people are telling GOT 9, it probably might… which model in Gemini are you using? People with 9 charts, exactly which is the model?
Krish Naik: I'm even not a fan of LLM-based chunking. It comes with a cost, even I don't have such controls. I always like rules-based chunking.
Krish Naik: Everybody is using OpenAI. Anybody with, okay, Gemini. In Gemini, which model?
Krish Naik: people working with Gemini, please let me know. Like, have you tested out the Gemini Pro 3, the Gemini 3 Pro model?
Krish Naik: Which is the best one, right now.
Krish Naik: Please don't use Gemini 2.5 flash.
Krish Naik: Sampath has used Gemini 3 Pro Preview, 8 chunks. Alright, you are also getting 8 chunks with Gemini 3 Pro Preview.
Krish Naik: Alright, now the token count, 9979. So always remember, this will be different.
Krish Naik: And generally, like, with this approach, I have lesser power with me, so I don't see that you should always go. Okay, because Dosi.
Krish Naik: Research paper comes.
Krish Naik: And really, they might tell you this is a good way.
Krish Naik: But it's not an optimal way to actually work with it.
Krish Naik: Okay, I don't feel that this is how you should do chanting.
Krish Naik: It should be rule-based summer.
Krish Naik: Because a lot of other things, because right now, if you really look into the content, it has not done any rephrased or any other stuff, because probably the requirement was not there.
Krish Naik: Okay, as per the poor implementation of Chunky, that is available. Okay, I can say that, yes, it was a research paper-based document, so really, they have not performed any rephrased operation, but I can say that this is not a very optimal window, at the last.
Krish Naik: Even in the chunky docs, if you really look into it, they have told that.
Krish Naik: This is the first agent tick chunker, okay? And really, agent, it means that they are actually using LLMs behind the scenes.
Krish Naik: Okay, and you can see it uses a reasoning part. So, how many of you feel that, when you look into your results, as for every student here, the number of chunks are varying?
Krish Naik: Okay, so simply based on this approach, I will say this is not a good approach, so don't use LLM-based charting approach.
Krish Naik: Okay, use anything, because… just think about every day, because document ingestion is a day-to-day thing. It means that every day documents will come, or every week it will come. You will have some frequency in your production. Do you think that for every time using an LLM,
Krish Naik: So, this is really not a good approach.
Krish Naik: Okay? It's not an embedding model, first of all, Cheta. I am using an LLM, I am not using an embedding model.
Krish Naik: This will change the output every time you run… I won't say, if the model is the same, E2317, it won't change the output every time if you use the same model. If you change the LLM model, then your output might be impacted.
Krish Naik: Okay, somebody is telling, okay, Share got, with GPT 4.1, 9 chance, because even I use GPT 4.1, in my case, it had 8 chance.
Krish Naik: Okay, so from here, you can understand, assembly, like, even the output of the LLM is different, and there is not a particular deterministic output. Generally in the field of chunking, we need deterministic output.
Krish Naik: Here, if your output changes for every execution, really, this is a bad technique.
Krish Naik: Okay, even it comes with a cost, that is the worst part. If it was free, then also I might have thought, but it always comes with a cost.
Krish Naik: So, simply remove this number. Initially, I will say, what you can use in production. Always test out the initial ones.
Krish Naik: The best friend is your recursive chunker. Okay, now I'm not talking about tables, I'm talking about simple text data. If you have code and chunkers, those are very specific use cases. Okay? But for now, just remember, majorly recursive characters, text splitter in Langchen, similarly here, you have the recursive chunker.
Krish Naik: This is really, really good.
Krish Naik: Okay, here you can pass anything, like markdown-based logics, you can create your own recursive rules, you have much more power.
Krish Naik: as anything. Like, semantic chunking, again, I can say that semantic chunking is good, but again, in few use cases, where you feel that your recursive fails then only move to semantic. Otherwise, don't move.
Krish Naik: Now, if you're trying to build an algorithm, just to evaluate which chunking is good, and if you really test it out, I can say in your experiments, more than 50% of the time, recursive chunker will come. Because I have already done that, but I'm telling you.
Krish Naik: Most of the time. So, always remember, this is, like, more than 50%, I can say, of the times recursive character is your best sign.
Krish Naik: If you have normal text data, that also I'm telling. Don't think about tables and code files. If you have simple text data, please stick to recursive chunkers.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: Recursive character is same, whether it's in Chongky, whether it's in Llama Index, or whether it's in Saa.
Krish Naik: Now, Samikhai is asking, is chunk is suitable for CSP files? Yes, you can use the table chunker.
Krish Naik: Because if you think about most of the CSV files, they will be having Edison, so it's pretty much like a team.
Krish Naik: Alright, now, you have done this part.
Krish Naik: Now, let's get back.
Krish Naik: to our… discretion of long minds.
Krish Naik: Because I think a lot of chunking we have really gone through.
Krish Naik: And a few other features are also there in Chonky that you can explore. I didn't feel that I need to discuss. For example, handshakes. Okay, now, they have the concept of handshake. Handshake means simply.
Krish Naik: If you have the chunks, you convert them into embeddings, and then you really push them. So, for example, here, if I'm talking about, let's take, which one is there? Like, majorly, we are using Quadrant.
Krish Naik: Okay, now they have a quadrant version, and they have created that, but I really don't feel I need to use Chong Key to do this. Directly using the quadrant package also I can do. Whenever you are using the quadrant client, through the quadrant client, it's a good practice always to use the core package, rather than always shifting.
Krish Naik: So, really, you can check this out, so I'm not going to discuss this part.
Krish Naik: Because this is just the creation of the embeddings and pushing them to VectorT.
Krish Naik: Now, same thing can be done using Langchain or using the core package.
Krish Naik: Alright guys, so now let's get back to Llama. Now, a little bit of more retrievers that we'll be talking about today.
Krish Naik: JSON… see, JSON and others, they are pretty much JSON, you can work. Even LanChain has that, Llama Index has that.
Krish Naik: And for JSONs, it will be pretty much the food-based chunk.
Krish Naik: It's debut.
Krish Naik: Alright, now I think we can get back.
Krish Naik: to this one.
Krish Naik: I think here are a few things that I have uploaded, so let's talk about…
Krish Naik: So, I'm pushing two files, right now. One is the advanced detectable.
Krish Naik: I'm going to know. Evaluation is same everywhere, whether it's Lama, Index, Langchen, they have might a separate model that we need to go. If you're working with Ragas, TBL, they… we don't want to focus on that.
Krish Naik: For complex documents, really, if you have multiple documents, the idea is that for every document, you need to define a chunking algorithm. Okay, parsing, you have to understand multi-parser and multi-chunking.
Krish Naik: both the things. If you have different and more complex documents at any point of time, okay, you will be having different parsing logic. Once everything is passed, then you'll be having different chunking logic.
Krish Naik: both levels. So you have to handle parsing as well as charging.
Krish Naik: You can do that, Mudassar, but really, you can create a simple for loop, and you can paste that, okay, and based on that, you can do the evaluation.
Krish Naik: There is no restriction in that part.
Krish Naik: But I feel that, do your experiments. If somebody wants to do, create a simple for loop, try to, keep all the implementations in one place, and then you can do an analysis also.
Krish Naik: Alright, now this file is not checked, I think, in GitHub, so let me just,
Krish Naik: push these two files. I have two files, just wait.
Krish Naik: This is the last.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, please have a check, to your repo, you will be getting that.
Krish Naik: The repo is exactly the same, the Lama Index one.
Krish Naik: because I thought about here, different type of retrievers are there, so… really, I feel that
Krish Naik: Few things are not available in Lanqing, so thought about discussing this part.
Krish Naik: Okay, so I think it has been pushed. Please provide a confirmation.
Krish Naik: Siembre po.
Krish Naik: The repo… the chonky repo is different, and the Llama index is different, so please have a check.
Krish Naik: I think, yes, advanced rate triple copy, okay, and the re-ranking copy, yes. These two are the ones.
Krish Naik: You can do a git pool also.
Krish Naik: Little bit about hierarchical structured documents and few other important things, I feel.
Krish Naik: Now, this is really the advanced part that we are going for Lama.
Krish Naik: Cool.
Krish Naik: Just take your time.
Krish Naik: Okay, it's going to be…
Krish Naik: 10.30, so if you want to have… do you guys want to start it after a break?
Krish Naik: Or should I continue? Let me know.
Krish Naik: Everybody, please let me.
Krish Naik: After a break, alright.
Krish Naik: Alright, let's go for a 10 minutes break, and then we'll… In the meantime, everybody, please be ready with the notebook, okay?
Krish Naik: the GitHub link is exactly the same of Llama Index.
Krish Naik: Why you ask for… I think you already have the links.
Krish Naik: Okay, just wait, I will share the repo link in chat.
Krish Naik: Just wait, I will stop sharing and start my clock, and then… Start our discussion.
Krish Naik: Where is clock?
Krish Naik: Alright guys, so let me know if everyone is back.
Krish Naik: What about others? Only one has stoled back.
Krish Naik: Alright, so… everybody has cloned.
Krish Naik: Or basically, have you performed a Git pull?
Krish Naik: Got the two notebooks.
Krish Naik: lots of dependency issues in this report. Only Sonali… okay, what about others? Please let me know.
Krish Naik: Because I don't think there will be dependency conflicts, because the packages are pretty much the same.
Krish Naik: Alright, at least try to execute the first step. Okay, I think the input should work for everyone.
Krish Naik: Balaja is telling you are getting an issue with respect to Llama Index LLM's Bedrock Converse. I'm not using Bedrock here, everything is based on OpenAI.
Krish Naik: I think the issue conflicts. Please, let me know, working for me, first cell, first cell, everybody please check the import cell. If the import doesn't work, nothing will work, that's why.
Krish Naik: Okay, import is successful, import is successful. So, Nali, please check from your side.
Krish Naik: Because it's the same environment, last time, the same environment.
Krish Naik: If you really look into, I'm using the same .vnk, I've not done any changes here.
Krish Naik: And I will be using OpenAI, I'm not using Bedrock.
Krish Naik: Imports are working.
Krish Naik: Okay, most of you are telling imports are working only.
Krish Naik: I think, Balaji told, no solution found for this one, hyphen frozen lactose cape.
Krish Naik: Please be sure, I'm not working with these two scripts. These two scripts have a requirement of that bedrock. Right now, I'm working with this advanced recurable copy, this notebook.
Krish Naik: And the other notebook will be hybrid search and re-ranking copy.
Krish Naik: Okay, so please have a check on that.
Krish Naik: Alright, so first of all, now you have to understand, now, this is the advanced retrieval part, the most advanced in LavaNet, so I thought about, let's talk a little bit, at least, about these things.
Krish Naik: Okay, so first of all comes your recursive retriever for any type of hierarchical document. Okay, so one example that we'll be creating, custom one, then comes to Query Fusion Retriever to combine multiple retrieval strategies together.
Krish Naik: Building custom retrievers, that particular with specialized ranking logic.
Krish Naik: applying query transformations, like Heidi, but right now we won't be discussing, but I have kept an implementation for Heidi. Little bit of Heidi fundamentals we'll be discussing, and probably on next Saturday, the pure Heidi will jump into.
Krish Naik: Then, coming to implementation of complex metadata filtering, so AND, OR, NOT logic. Very similar to logics that we have previously done during the LanChen implementation with Quadrite. But this time, I won't be using any third-party vector store directly, the core vector store, through Lama Index that I'll be showing you.
Krish Naik: Alright.
Krish Naik: Now, wrap up, please have a check.
Krish Naik: Okay, see, guys, the requirements… Whenever I'm talking about the requirement, no matching distribution form.
Krish Naik: just wheat.
Krish Naik: Quadrant, comma… okay. So here, just check, okay, based on the error, 1L of llama index is missing. Okay.
Krish Naik: So, just try to, take that part. 1L, because of that Naga, you might be getting an error. See, guys, always check at least the error, rather than directly pasting it, okay?
Krish Naik: The llama index, the llama spelling was wrong.
Krish Naik: Okay, so when I looked into it directly, I decoded it.
Krish Naik: And right now, I'm not using these packages, first of all, just to clarify for everyone, I'm not using Bedra for Converse. This I have kept just for this script execution.
Krish Naik: Okay, is this part clear?
Krish Naik: What was the issue?
Krish Naik: Alright.
Krish Naik: When you look into the era, please always have a look, at least, what is going on, why you are getting that.
Krish Naik: Alright, so let's start our discussion on the advanced victory bill part.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, let me execute the initial cell. Okay, the core imports are successfully working. So, here are really a lot of new imports that you might see, one coming from the core part, so these things you guys have already worked with.
Krish Naik: Now, then comes schema definition. So, schema definition, I'll be working with text node, index nodes, and nodes with score. Now, these are very specifically for defining any document schema. In those cases, it will be helpful to me.
Krish Naik: So that's why, like, every document can be based on some hierarchy, and through that, we can define multiple notes. So your text note comes, your index note comes. So when I'll be doing the implementation, I'll be showing you.
Krish Naik: Now, can you see here how many types of retriever I have imported?
Krish Naik: All the majors, like, what are the… this retriever you guys have already gone through previously?
Krish Naik: You have done that?
Krish Naik: vector index retriever and the vector index auto retriever, both implementations. Right now, I'm not taking the auto version, because in the previous notebook, it was there already.
Krish Naik: Okay? So, only these 3 are the major new ones. And why I have taken a base retriever? Base retriever, it means that whenever you are creating a custom retriever, so you have to inherit some properties from the base retriever. So, because of that, the base retriever, here I have taken.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: Then comes your retriever query engine. Okay, so this is your, query engine, this is the default one, there is nothing changed. Then you have ID transformations, like, if you want to work with hypothetical documents in those cases, I'll be talking a little bit about ID, what is IDE?
Krish Naik: Then comes transformations, so if you want to perform query transformations, in that case, the transform query engine is really important, and generally, for ID-based implementations, you need a transformed query engine.
Krish Naik: Then, few imports I have with respect to metadata filter. So, right now, you can see I am using… I'll be using the core vector store, okay, the default one from Llama, not third party, because for third party.
Krish Naik: Whatever the operations that we'll be doing, you need to have a support. It means that, for quadrant, it will be different. For Chroma, it will be different. So, the core mean
Krish Naik: The default vector store, which is available from Llama, will be only using that.
Krish Naik: Now, here I have my OpenAI part. Everything is configured based on OpenAI. If you want to change it, you can switch to something different.
Krish Naik: What is the difference between? If you want to apply multiple filters, then metadata filters. If you want to apply a single filter, then metadata filter. That's the only difference.
Krish Naik: Alright, so I think this part should be working. Now, let's do the global settings configuration.
Krish Naik: So, here I passed GPT4Room Mini, okay, and text embedding 3 is more.
Krish Naik: Now, first of all, as we will be working with a recursive one, so here you can see the recursive retriever. Okay, so for this one, I could define one hierarchical structure of document.
Krish Naik: Now, just try to analyze the document. This is pretty much nested document.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, the… in the first stage of the document, you have four things with respect to paper.
Krish Naik: Okay, so, research paper, attention is all you need, authors, year, citations, category, transformers… Okay, now, later on, I'll be using these categories even for our metadata filtering also.
Krish Naik: Now, there is some abstract.
Krish Naik: Now, later on, now this is where your actual hierarchy takes place, where I have multiple sections. So, this becomes a single unit.
Krish Naik: Can we see?
Krish Naik: and hierarchical document exactly how the structure has been defined. So I can say this is just, like, the introduction part, and then probably you have multiple paragraphs within that.
Krish Naik: Everybody, the structure, is this part clear? Similarly, I have for birth.
Krish Naik: Similarly, I have for rack.
Krish Naik: So, core documents, 3. When you try to execute this.
Krish Naik: You'll be getting. So, created 3 research papers with hierarchical structure, attention is all you need. Okay, with 3 sections, both with 3 sections, and then comes your rag with 3 sections.
Krish Naik: I think this part should be executing for everybody. Probably you might get an error in the hierarchical… in the recursive retriever part.
Krish Naik: I think for everybody, it's working EAS, it's like JSON. Correct. It's like JSON. Pretty much nested structure that you have.
Krish Naik: Now, coming to recursive retriever. So, where we do use? So, generally, when in hierarchical structure. The structure, here we have already defined, like, paper with sections, books with chapters, in those cases.
Krish Naik: Now, the top-level notes, which is basically the summary, the abstract.
Krish Naik: Generally abstract form in the first part of the research paper, and then you have your headaches in major research papers, if you look into that. It's how the structure has been defined.
Krish Naik: So, the top-level notes define only the summaries of the abstract. Then comes your detailed notes, which have your… Now, don't think about this node as chunks, okay? A few people might think.
Krish Naik: Because right now, I have not used any type of notebar section. It's simple nodes that I'm referring. It means that some subsections, so full sections or chapters.
Krish Naik: And then finally, we'll be implementing our, recursive retriever, okay, which will retrieve some top-level documents, okay? And then we'll be, going through the details of that.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, let's try to build the structure. So, here, I have taken a few blank things. Okay, so blank links for all nodes, then I have my index notes, which is the representation of a top-level summary.
Krish Naik: Okay, and then I have a retriever tick. I'll be showing you what will be the content of the retriever tick after I perform an append operation.
Krish Naik: Now, already I have my papers here, so simply, you can… if you want, you can print out this information. So, like, for example, here.
Krish Naik: Just look into this paper data.
Krish Naik: TP1, please do it, I have not done it.
Krish Naik: Okay, so you'll be getting exactly what is the information, how the structure has been defined.
Krish Naik: Now, a simple for loop. The idea is to iterate over all of your nodes, mean the top nodes, the subnodes.
Krish Naik: So, for a paper, so initially, I'm taking a subsection notes, a blank list, later on, on top of that, I'll be appending the information.
Krish Naik: So, first section in the paper. Now, can you see that I am accessing it through the text node?
Krish Naik: Take note refers to a subnote.
Krish Naik: Okay? So whenever you are trying to build the schema, so right now, I will try to prepare a schema, through that schema, because all the information that I'll be capturing, I'll be keeping in this, like, blank.
Krish Naik: variables for now, which can be a deck and which can be a list. So right now, majorly, you will be looking into the list part.
Krish Naik: Only for deck ease, I'll be keeping my core three documents.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, let's try to go step by step. So, as you can see, for section, in paper sections. So, simply just go through this part, and you will be getting this section key through which we can actually access it.
Krish Naik: Now, let's start creating the nodes. So, the text node, text section contact, and finally, the metadata.
Krish Naik: Just try to analyze this part, guys, because it's simply a parsing logic on top of the content.
Krish Naik: How many of you are clear with this? And once the parsing is done, so step-by-step, I have taken and append operation once.
Krish Naik: Okay?
Krish Naik: Pure Python stuff. Please take your time, take 30 seconds, and go through this.
Krish Naik: Yes, building nodes with a subnote.
Krish Naik: Now, Zayworthy Cesar is asking, why manual parsing?
Krish Naik: How we will, automate that? Tell me.
Krish Naik: You have to understand the structure, then only you can do it, no? If you don't know the structure.
Krish Naik: Then how will… you can make it automated?
Krish Naik: Nileima, print out the, variable you can directly look, look into, where… so, first of all, the section notes. So, using text node, you create a…
Krish Naik: It can be any node. So right now, if you look into here, text, that is basically for the section.
Krish Naik: Thus, basically, when I'm talking about section is basically the sub part. The, if you really look into this content, this is where section comes into the picture.
Krish Naik: Try to analyze through the document.
Krish Naik: All nodes will have both the nodes, the parent node as well as your subnodes.
Krish Naik: Alright, see, simply, let's try to execute and just print out the information. In that way, it will become better.
Krish Naik: Alright, so top-level summary notes.
Krish Naik: How many nodes are there? 3 nodes. And section-level nodes, you have nine.
Krish Naik: Now, why this structure is coming? Just previously, we have already gone through this.
Krish Naik: Created 3 research papers. Now, these three research papers have that abstract note, if I talk about that introduction, but if you really think about, in every paper, 1-1-1 section. So, that's, like, 3 sections. And how many total subsections you have? Three sections, 3 sections, 3 sections. That's why, based on that, you have total three sections.
Krish Naik: Is this part clear?
Krish Naik: Just print out the variables. I'm not printing out the variables every time, but you can actually print out all nodes. Just take a print statement, or simply print it here.
Krish Naik: what you are getting, check.
Krish Naik: 3 sub-notes of the attention paper, 3 sub-notes of the BERT paper.
Krish Naik: Okay, now coming to index-level notes.
Krish Naik: Just try to print out the information. If you don't print out, you won't understand.
Krish Naik: Only 3 nodes. Is this part clear?
Krish Naik: Are you creating the metadata? Yes.
Krish Naik: Yes, we are doing that.
Krish Naik: So that's why you are getting this information here in metadata.
Krish Naik: Is this part clear from how we have done the parsing of a hierarchical structure?
Krish Naik: Generally, whenever you are working with JSON, you have to work in this way. And even you can print out the retrieval dict keys, so you will get the actual keys through which you can access the entire content.
Krish Naik: the major dict piece. So, retriever underscore dict, if you look here, this is a blank one, and on top of that, we were appendix. So, through this, I'm creating the metadata also.
Krish Naik: For every summary note, we are actually creating the metadata.
Krish Naik: manually, yes. So, when you look into the metadata, so it is vital, because very specifically, I have told you have to access the information through this nested structure.
Krish Naik: So, just look into this cell. This is pure passing and nothing more.
Krish Naik: Is this part…
Krish Naik: done. This is very customized, as we know, the structure has made sense. Yes, this part, like, few people might find it difficult, but it's pure Python. There is not a lot of tough things going on. It's pretty much straightforward.
Krish Naik: Alright, now, first of all, we'll be looking into the top level, those three indexes, the core ones.
Krish Naik: Now, the top-level index, so here, even if you look into…
Krish Naik: Okay, so once we have, basically done the initial parsing, so after that, we are creating a paper index.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, you will see that I will be creating multiple indexes here. So, first of all, the vector store index, now this is purely, and here, what is the information that I am saving? My section notes.
Krish Naik: Okay? So, section notes from here, simply, the section nodes.op. So, one by one, section nodes that will be taken into account. And please, look, this is under the main for loop.
Krish Naik: Okay, not inside this one. So you do have inside the main loop, and here are your section nodes that have been defined. So, this is also within a
Krish Naik: Now, in the next step, so once you have defined your vector store index, now let's try to create a retriever. And very specifically here.
Krish Naik: Now, this is a node retriever object that we are creating. The retriever deck, paper title. Now, for every one, we are just looking into the title.
Krish Naik: And this information will be saved. So whenever we will be doing a retrieve operation, the first level of logic will always come to the paper title. It means that through that, you will be accessing any other content within the document.
Krish Naik: Okay, so it will always try to find the paper title, so that's why this is the first level of retriever that we are creating.
Krish Naik: Okay, and this information, you can access it through. So, what are the main, top-level notes in simple terms?
Krish Naik: So if you want to access those nodes through this, retrieverDict, variable I'll be accessing. And later on, I have printed it also for your reference, so exactly through which I'll be accessing the data.
Krish Naik: Now, in the next step, creating the summary notes. So this is your main top-level notes, and in that, we have that metadata information. So for that, all those information, step-by-step, even the paper title, that data also we are accessing.
Krish Naik: the paper abstract, that also we are accessing, and finally, we are creating this note. So, these notes when I'm talking.
Krish Naik: Okay? So, step by step. So, two levels of information that I have created for the same document.
Krish Naik: Now, let's get here. So, first of all, let's create a,
Krish Naik: the first index with respect to the vector store. Now, you can see that here I have created one index. This is… this was for a different purpose. Now, here I have taken another one, and this is for a different purpose. Now, I will try to create that… your hierarchical structure. First of all, let's include the top-level indexes.
Krish Naik: So, in this top-level indexes, I am passing my index notes. So, index notes previously you have printed, or otherwise you can print the information again if you want to get that. Now, the idea is to iterate over it, so one by one, we are accessing the paper title through the index ID, and similarly, your index object through your paper title.
Krish Naik: Now, if you want, try to print out each variable one by one.
Krish Naik: Okay? Now, in the next step.
Krish Naik: Another, now, as the vector store is defined. Now, here, I can initialize my retriever. So, this is my as retriever. So, now.
Krish Naik: Once the index is created on top of that, I am adding my retrieval operation. So, retriever ticked, and very specifically, the key-through vector that I am passing, the top-level index as the retriever, and we have simply passed that
Krish Naik: Just, find the top two, okay?
Krish Naik: documents for us. And then I'm creating my recursive retriever. Okay, and in the recursive retriever, first of all, the index that I have defined here, through which the vector index part, then I have my retriever ticked.
Krish Naik: where I have all the keys defined. So here, I have all the keys defined. Okay, and then verbose is equal to true, just to print out the information.
Krish Naik: Now, really, like, this part is a bit advanced. If you want, you can print out each information one by one.
Krish Naik: Because this is a hierarchy level. Till now, either in Langchen, you have seen this. This is the first time I'm showing you this.
Krish Naik: Generally, we don't teach this, but I thought about, let's keep it. It is hard, but try to print out each information. If you're not printing out the variables, it's harder to get the intuition.
Krish Naik: Now, Muhammad is asking, how practical is it to… see, this is examples I'm telling. It totally depends upon your use case. In your use case, do you need that or not?
Krish Naik: Okay, if you're working with hierarchical-level documents, then only you will be taking this particular approach, because this is a little bit…
Krish Naik: outside your main implementations. Okay, this is much more a nested level than only it comes, so thought about showing you guys. This is tough, I know, because if you really think it's not tough, it's just the implementation when you look in.
Krish Naik: Okay, and just confirm me, this cell is recruiting for everybody, because here you might get an error.
Krish Naik: Okay, probably, just confirms. Everybody, please confirm. And wherever you have an issue, please try to print that out.
Krish Naik: Try to add more print statements and simple tops.
Krish Naik: Everybody, please let me know. Only a few people are letting. It looks like for others, going above your head.
Krish Naik: It's not only about working, please use print statements. Because for every piece of code, like, I cannot add a lot of print statements.
Krish Naik: Okay, so just wherever you feel, just create a new cell and print that out. If it is in a for loop, pass within a print statement.
Krish Naik: When you are working with nested geophones, SK. As simple as that.
Krish Naik: A simple JSON, even with nested YMLs also you can…
Krish Naik: Because every document incorporate.
Krish Naik: It totally depends upon the file types.
Krish Naik: Majorly, because this is a real-time example that you might feel, because I feel that this…
Krish Naik: is much more, because it's not always about simple documents, okay? If you work with hierarchical documents, in those cases, you have.
Krish Naik: Mitesh, can you explain why two indexes?
Krish Naik: Created one for your top level, and one for your subsection.
Krish Naik: The idea is not to keep everything in one place.
Krish Naik: We can work with one, but the retrieval is not efficient methods in that case.
Krish Naik: That's the thing, the idea is to make your retrieval much more better.
Krish Naik: Basically, you flat it out, yes. Alright. Now, I have initialized my recursive character, recursive retriever here.
Krish Naik: Okay? Then, in the next step, simply, like, I will try to pass in query. So, if you really look into query, how does the transformer architecture handle sequential data? A simple question that I have asked here, okay?
Krish Naik: And this is a… these statements are useless, so skip all the print statements for now. Now, here is the main initialization. Nodes is equal to where I'll be getting my core nodes, so recursiveRetriever.retrieve, and then I'm passing my query.
Krish Naik: Okay, and then finally, I'm going through all the nodes one by one, and I'm accessing all the metadata through that. Okay, now, let's try to just look into the output. From the output only, you will feel that this is different.
Krish Naik: Okay, so first of all, this is the query that I have. Now, simple. The two print statements. Now, from here, your actual retrieval starts, the node initialization. So, can you see here, based on the query that I have, the transformer? So, first of all, where it is going.
Krish Naik: It is trying to fetch, okay, based on the question that I have, how the transformer architecture handles sequential data. So, it means that you need to find the key, the retriever dict key. So, what is that? That is your attention is all you need, the first stage.
Krish Naik: Then you will come to the subsection.
Krish Naik: So, two levels of fetching that you were entering.
Krish Naik: How many of you got the thing that I'm trying to explain?
Krish Naik: Because here, actually, two levels of retrieving is happening. First of all, your top level…
Krish Naik: Then your subsection within that.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, read tape, node ID, entering. Now, this is the name of the node. I know that attention is all you need is the mean. So, if you really looked into that print statement here, this is the actual key. So, first it needs to go inside this one, then only it can access the information.
Krish Naik: Yes, one.
Krish Naik: Mama, like determining the relevant title when dig into… correct.
Krish Naik: First, try to find what is relevant, then try to go deeper into that.
Krish Naik: That is the intuition behind this. And generally, this sub-level, it really works good.
Krish Naik: Okay, so first of all, when you look into, yes, the attention is all you need, this part is coming. Then, coming to the text node, okay, this is the actual information that you have here.
Krish Naik: Then coming, another node, which is, RNNs are written, some core information about that.
Krish Naik: Okay, and you can see here, it has even faced another
Krish Naik: key. It means that another birth also it got. It is not only that, if it got one result, through that it is trying to access only that.
Krish Naik: Okay, so Mudhasar is asking root search, correct? The first root-level search that you are doing with respect to the keys, and then it finds within that. And it's not only that, if it finds only one root key, probably that content can be some other. Your… the content that you were trying to find, it can be on two levels of nodes also.
Krish Naik: Is this part clear? Because from every node, you're right now, from the first node of attention, you are trying to get two nodes. From this node also, you are trying to get two nodes. So in that way, you are trying to fetch the information. So, this is simple information fetching.
Krish Naik: And nothing.
Krish Naik: Now, I feel that this is a powerful…
Krish Naik: Okay, I don't know how many of you agree, totally depends upon your use case, but if you're working with such nested, such a document, it is real.
Krish Naik: If your data is hierarchical, or if you can transform your data into hierarchical structure, that is the other way around. Sometimes I have seen, we do data manipulation. It means that on top of the original content, you will just restructure the content.
Krish Naik: through keys and buttons. What does?
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: Nagarpan, while going for the second key, does the search start from the initial document? Yes.
Krish Naik: Whatever the text nodes will be there, or basically your subnodes within your community, it will try to access through that.
Krish Naik: Known to the subnode scoring, it can be different, because there, your top data similarities will take place.
Krish Naik: Yes, yes, yes, Puvandiram, you can add more and more retrieval, but this was somewhere. It uses cosine, yes, yes, by default, it will use the cosine distance only.
Krish Naik: Now, for parsing, hierarchical data, can a library be used like unstructured? Yes, unstructured can also be used. There, you have a very specific JSON-based module. Okay, but that is only for parsing, more than.
Krish Naik: Okay, here it's the… not only the parsing. First, we did a manual-based parsing, and we wrote our custom logic, then on top of the retrible. So, a two-level retrieval, that was the idea. It means that first you search the parent, then you find out the child.
Krish Naik: But it's not that only one parent only you are looking into. Your content might be in some other parent's house.
Krish Naik: So, from every chart, you are trying to find that country.
Krish Naik: Because if you would think only from JSON, JSON can be directly loaded up through lagchain. But the idea is to focus only on the retrieval. The idea is not on passing. Everybody please try to get that.
Krish Naik: To build a hierarchy, I need a parser, so a manual parser that I have done. But the core focus I want to show you, that nested level retrieval.
Krish Naik: That was my core idea.
Krish Naik: Rajat is asking a big MLC,
Krish Naik: This is done by data science team. It really depends upon the use case.
Krish Naik: Many people are asking our people.
Krish Naik: Now, really, this is a simple structure. For me, you can have much more nested structure.
Krish Naik: So, really, I cannot say that… it totally depends upon the use case, guys. My core purpose was to show you.
Krish Naik: this particular example, because I feel that this is a powerful tool.
Krish Naik: And people are actually working with JSON.
Krish Naik: I know every organization is working with Jessica.
Krish Naik: If there… how many of you think nobody's using JSON in today's world?
Krish Naik: Okay, so that's why I just kept the example.
Krish Naik: Alright, now let's look into some other. Now, we will take,
Krish Naik: to the next level. Okay, so let's try to work with respect to query fusion.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, I'll be talking about Fusion later on, but let's try to look into a few implementations here. Because, directly, a few concepts are there with respect to hybrid search that needs to be discussed, but for now, let's focus on…
Krish Naik: So, the Query Fusion Retriever, where you'll be combining multiple strategies. Okay, so why Query Fusion? So, different retrievers excel at different tasks.
Krish Naik: Okay, now we will see that I'll be creating multiple retrievers. Okay.
Krish Naik: Through Query Fusion IB, Actually, like, accessing those.
Krish Naik: Now, first of all, a vector retriever. This, you guys already know, there is nothing new.
Krish Naik: Now, one new retriever, the keyword retriever, where it will try to find an exert term matching.
Krish Naik: So once is basically a simple then search, okay, the first example, and then comes your term search, a keyword matching. So that's why the name keyword retriever that we have given.
Krish Naik: Okay? And then finally, you have your metadata retriever.
Krish Naik: So, another retriever we are just building, okay, for our metadata.
Krish Naik: Now, this is totally new. So, generally, we don't create a retriever only for metadata. Okay, but I'm showing you an example. I feel that this is really powerful.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, to further retrieve us, what are the things that we need?
Krish Naik: So, let's get, now the idea is to send to access the data through PayPal data. So, that's why
Krish Naik: I have passed all those things, and we are capturing the metadata through this particular key.
Krish Naik: And all the information, I'm creating the document. Can you see here the document class? So, using the document class, I'm creating the actual information. So this format, I know you guys have already
Krish Naik: I looked into the previous classes of Llama Intel. Please, let me know.
Krish Naik: Because syntactically, it might be hard for a few people, but it's simple llama only, okay? Through Python object, and this information, I'm adding it on top of the flat documents.
Krish Naik: Are there equivalents in other architectures?
Krish Naik: What are the other architectures, SK, that you were referring?
Krish Naik: Okay, then, first of all, this is the first level of document, now coming to the subsections within your section notes. For them, I have this.
Krish Naik: So, if you really look into everything I am appending within the flat documents.
Krish Naik: This is the blank list, and for every operation, and you can see this is your main for loop, so everything is within the main, for loop.
Krish Naik: Okay, so let me just execute this.
Krish Naik: And just try to look into this, variable, exactly what is the content.
Krish Naik: Okay, so simply pass it here.
Krish Naik: So, what is the information that I have?
Krish Naik: This is… All the transformation. It's not only top-level and sub-level.
Krish Naik: And I have all the information.
Krish Naik: It means that all those. Previously, I created a different one, but this time, everything is pretty much a flattening operation, so that's why the variable name is flat underscore documents. Is this part clear? Through this piece of code, what we have done? Simple, a pure parsing.
Krish Naik: And then finally, I've created a vector store in text form documents.
Krish Naik: Later on, I'll be accessing that.
Krish Naik: Alright.
Krish Naik: Now, let's talk up. Now, this is where the magic comes.
Krish Naik: Okay, so 3 levels we have decided. So, first of all, your vector index retriever.
Krish Naik: Okay, so multiple retrievers with different strategies, that's why I've kept it. First one is the Retriever 1, high similarity threshold. This is precision focus. It means that the idea is to only focus on high similarity, and nothing more right now.
Krish Naik: Now, here I am passing the fusion index, which previously I've defined, and from here I am looking into the top side document.
Krish Naik: Now, coming to lower the threshold, more the result. So, similarly, the threshold part
Krish Naik: Okay, this is much more recall-focused, I can say, so you can play with these parameters, you can make it much more smaller, you can increase it here. So, simply, you can lower this value, you can make it 3, 2, totally depends upon your wish. Now, this is completely a hyperparameter that needs to be decided by you.
Krish Naik: Okay? So, one level of retriever, which is the precision level, the idea is to focus on, then comes your recall level.
Krish Naik: And then, finally, this fusion retriever. So, this is a query fusion retriever, where I am passing my setup retrievers.
Krish Naik: And finally, I'm looking into the final set of documents that will be retrained.
Krish Naik: And then comes the number of queries, so generate one query. So, generally, here, that, generating hypothetical document embedding that comes into the picture, and mode is reciprocal reliant. Okay, now, this is a little bit advanced, this particular topic of RRS, I'll be discussing when I'll be talking in hybrid search.
Krish Naik: But I want to show you this feature.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: Because, really, like, this is one of the most…
Krish Naik: Advanced way of defining all of your retrievals in one shot.
Krish Naik: Okay, because till now, neither in Langshan, we have done such implementations, but I feel that this is powerful, where you can actually look into and manipulate
Krish Naik: A lot of things.
Krish Naik: Now, how you want? Because, can we create retrievers? One can only focus on precision, and one can focus on recall.
Krish Naik: So, based on that, you can always change the values. So, most of the time, during recall-focused, we can lower the similarity part.
Krish Naik: But for precision, always try to keep higher similarity.
Krish Naik: Alright, now, what are the new things here that you guys don't know about?
Krish Naik: one that I feel is, this mode, okay? So, reciprocal re-ranked Fusion, so this is RRF. Now.
Krish Naik: Little bit late, talk about this concept, and then we will jump into the other part of the network.
Krish Naik: It will be better to give a few minutes for going through, or that you guys can go through it, a little bit talk about the theory also.
Krish Naik: I feel that,
Krish Naik: This part is a little bit tough to get, but yeah, it's not very tough option.
Krish Naik: So let me start sharing mine.
Krish Naik: Notepad.
Krish Naik: Please provide a confirmation that it is visible or not.
Krish Naik: I think it is visible.
Krish Naik: Okay, so, few things, in this.
Krish Naik: The concept of Heidi, in the next class, we'll be talking about this, okay? So, these are…
Krish Naik: Hypothetical, so that at least in the next class, I don't need to start from scratch, okay? So, hypothetical document embeddings.
Krish Naik: In the next class, I'll be showing you the research paper also.
Krish Naik: Okay. Now, in simple terms, like, what is IDE? Okay, now, this is used in information retrieval systems, guys.
Krish Naik: Okay? And, now, the idea is to generate questions, so that's why hypothetical document embeddings.
Krish Naik: Okay, and this is one shot of zero shot.
Krish Naik: the retrieval.
Krish Naik: Okay, so simple, like, zero-shot learning. Now, this is zero-shot, and very specifically, let me add the term dense also, because we are working with vectors right now, so it will be a dense directory.
Krish Naik: Now, what will happen? It will generate… so, according to the algorithm, it will generate hypothetical document.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: Generate.
Krish Naik: Ed… Hypothetical document.
Krish Naik: Okay? Using a LLM. Always remember, it will be using a LLM. This is the first step.
Krish Naik: You'll be generating a document, then you will be encoding this document.
Krish Naik: Okay? And during the encoding part, you will be using an algorithm. So, for example, there are multiple types of algorithms, but let's focus on the core one as mentioned in the research paper, which is contrastive learning.
Krish Naik: This is a machine learning algorithm.
Krish Naik: Anybody has learned in machine learning, contrastive learning?
Krish Naik: No, okay, nobody has learned in machine learning. I will just give you a high-level overview. Okay, now, the question comes.
Krish Naik: this particular approach. Now, first of all, let's focus a little bit on constructive learning, because a few people are telling, yes, we know, and few people are telling no. A lot of no's, I can see. So, let's try to understand what is. So, this particular learning, this is an ML
Krish Naik: Okay, so this generally comes under machine learning.
Krish Naik: And what is the main purpose? So, this is a machine learning technique where the machine learning models learns to differentiate between similar and dissimilar data points. Okay, that's why the name contrastive comes in the first place.
Krish Naik: Differentiate.
Krish Naik: Between… You're similar?
Krish Naik: And dissimilar data points.
Krish Naik: Okay, now this is a fundamental idea behind it. And majorly, contrastive learning, we do use it in the field of documentary. Okay, now, the cons… generally, this algorithm. Okay, now, so, in simple terms, can I say this is a differentiating algorithm?
Krish Naik: Which will differentiate between your similar and dissimilar data points.
Krish Naik: Yes? Now, this particular contrastive, learning algorithm, what it will try to learn. So, first of all, it will try to learn
Krish Naik: Representation.
Krish Naik: This is the most important thing, the document representation.
Krish Naik: Okay, so representation of documents for now, I will just keep it in that way.
Krish Naik: Okay, so the idea is to represent the documents, okay? So, in a way that it will find similar documents which are close together in a representational space. So, the idea is, if you think about a high-dimension space.
Krish Naik: In that high-dimensional space, Can I say that similar documents will be close to one another?
Krish Naik: and dissimilar.
Krish Naik: Will be far away.
Krish Naik: Okay, so similarly, you can think about, this is cluster 1.
Krish Naik: pop similar document. Okay, there will be another cluster, because,
Krish Naik: Okay, and when I'm telling far away, it means that the dissimilar documents will be far away from the similar documents. They'll be pretty much far apart.
Krish Naik: Alright, now, in this way, you actually try to create an efficient similarity-based retrieval system. So, this actually helps you to create an efficient
Krish Naik: I can say, embedding-based retrieval system.
Krish Naik: Okay? One of the common examples are MRL.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, a simple example I have taken as contrastive learning here, but there are much more advanced algorithms, according to research, and a few people might have heard of it also. MRL, how many people have heard about this MRL?
Krish Naik: Matroshka. Representation. Learning.
Krish Naik: Yes.
Krish Naik: Yeah, I said in the first class, okay? Alright, I know people with Gemini. If you go to the docs, right now for creating embeddings, okay, so this is really good. MRI. Similarly, your contrastive learning was previously used or not.
Krish Naik: So that's why I'm just going into this. So, this is Matroshka with the presentation done.
Krish Naik: Okay? You can do the paper of this one. So, through Matroshka, basically all of your Gemini models they use, if you look into the recent embedding models which are launching, most of them are using Matroshka representation.
Krish Naik: Okay? So, another advanced, simple, pure noun that I'm telling you.
Krish Naik: Alright, now, whenever you are working with creating embedding models, then only. But in your case, you don't need to create embedding models, so don't worry about this particular approach.
Krish Naik: Okay, so first of all, let's look into that entire process of breaking down Heidi, so exactly how I will try to break.
Krish Naik: So, the first step… As I told that.
Krish Naik: In any RAT system, the user will pass any type of query. The first step is getting the query.
Krish Naik: input.
Krish Naik: Yes, you will ask a question, the user will submit some type of question or a query. Now, in the next step, okay, you will be generating a document. Now, this is where your hypothetical document generation will come.
Krish Naik: And this will be using LLM.
Krish Naik: This is not an actual document, okay? And generally, these are terms by instruction-based LLM. Anyone, any LLM which can follow instructions, generally, like GPT-4, usually most of the LLMs are instruction-based, so there won't be any type of problem.
Krish Naik: Now, the document that will be generated, okay, it will try to capture some type of relevance patterns. Always remember, some type of relevance patterns will be there.
Krish Naik: That's why I'm telling the relevance patterns, not the actual… okay, but, not the actual factual content, but there can be errors also.
Krish Naik: So, when you are generating this hypothetical document, I cannot say that this document is 100% correct.
Krish Naik: I will say that, yes, it can be 20% correct, 30% correct. Generally, the amount is very, very low, but you will have a lot of errors also.
Krish Naik: This is the first step, okay, to generate this document. Now in the third step.
Krish Naik: Once this particular document is generated, then the document embedding process that happens.
Krish Naik: Alright, I made the mistake.
Krish Naik: Your contrastive learning comes here, no? So, it's not embedding, it's encoding.
Krish Naik: Okay?
Krish Naik: So, and and whenever I'm talking about this contrastive learning, that is an unsupervised machine learning algorithm.
Krish Naik: Okay, so one of the most common examples of contrastive learned encoders are contraver. I don't know if you guys have heard about this.
Krish Naik: Generally, redone.
Krish Naik: teach it, in these classes, so this is pretty much advanced. So, there is a model, an example model that I am telling that you can do a research. Okay, now these, type of encoders, now, this is actually an encoder, okay? And contrastive encoder.
Krish Naik: For now, as we are doing an encoding operation, that's why… and this is completely unsupervised algorithm.
Krish Naik: unsupervised, so that's why I'm writing. It's not unsupervised algorithm.
Krish Naik: Now, this particular, this enc… so whenever you are working with any encoders, what will happen? It will use, for example, right now, a contributor for now. Let's take our unsupervised contrastive, encoder is contribver.
Krish Naik: This will convert the hypothetical document into the embedding vector.
Krish Naik: So, finally, through our contraver, so for here, if I take, you'll be getting your embeddex.
Krish Naik: Okay, and these are hypothetical embeddings, guys.
Krish Naik: Because my document is also hypothetical. Everything is hypothetical here.
Krish Naik: Now, on top of that, we perform a similarity search.
Krish Naik: Because we already have the user query, the system will use, basically, the vector to find real documents in the corpus. So, in whichever dataset you have, it will try to find the real document.
Krish Naik: So, can you think about… now, this approach is a little bit different.
Krish Naik: Okay, and finally, you will have your retrieval results.
Krish Naik: So, when you are performing the similarity search, it will find on real documents. This search will be taking on real documents.
Krish Naik: It means you are creating hypothetical embeddings, but using those embeddings, you are actually trying to find on top of your original set of documents.
Krish Naik: Okay, so let me just try to find some slow example, okay, and let me take one image, I think that will be better. So, somewhere from…
Krish Naik: I think… This one I can take from somewhere, okay? So…
Krish Naik: Alright.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, let me just… sounds Russian… okay, Mathroshka, yes. Mathrozka dolls are there in Russia, which is famous, correct? Samiksha is hypothetical documents generated using both query and retrieve embeddings. Not retrieve embeddings, but based on the query.
Krish Naik: Okay. Now, Sanjeev, if you are going… if you have a big query, will Heidi have more errors, or less relevancy? If your query is bigger, for sure it will have lesser relevance.
Krish Naik: Why would we create a hypothetical embedding? Because through that hypothetical embedding, you can perform a better search.
Krish Naik: Okay, so let me just take that, image, I brought it here, I think.
Krish Naik: This is actually a bigger image, I think.
Krish Naik: Okay. The core part.
Krish Naik: Now, the core things, for example, simple one that I have taken right now.
Krish Naik: Okay, so, regular RAG, the idea is you perform a direct encoding and search the documents and retrieve the similar chunk. This always happens with respect to any type of regular RAG.
Krish Naik: Okay? Then comes the idea of working with ID. So, where you'll be generating hypothetical document, import the
Krish Naik: And whenever we use the term encoding, it means that through that, we'll be generating the embeddings, okay? And then search the document charts.
Krish Naik: It means that using that hypothetical, embedding that we have generated from our hypothetical document, we will try to perform as such on top of our original, or real data, which is available on top of our vector databases, and then we will try to return.
Krish Naik: So, when you try to take this approach, okay, so, generally we have seen, okay, it will improve the retrieval, generally, for complex queries that we have seen. Then, narrowing down your semantic gap, this operation also takes place.
Krish Naik: Okay, and finally, like, bridging domain terminology gap. Really, like, this operation, I feel it less happens when your complete context changes, it really doesn't work.
Krish Naik: But, like, the idea is to generate hypothetical document, and through that generation, you want to perform some type of retrieval task.
Krish Naik: And, the major ones. So, for example, a simple example, I have kept it here.
Krish Naik: So, recent advancements in diabetes treatments include… okay, now, for example, here, one that has been given is… no, really, now, this information which is generated, it's not necessary that it is always correct.
Krish Naik: It means that the facts which are there, it can be wrong also.
Krish Naik: Now, generally, why wrong? Okay, now the question comes, if we have some wrong information, how it can make the improvement?
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: Now, just think about, here, if you have to think about, little bit about blind tests.
Krish Naik: Okay. Whenever you are trying to pass any information. Okay. So, do you think that in one shot you will be getting the correct result?
Krish Naik: How many of you think that in one shot you'll be getting the correct result?
Krish Naik: Yes? Is it possible?
Krish Naik: In one shot, it is not possible. The idea is that at least through your ID, okay, you will try to generate something wrong.
Krish Naik: If through something wrong, you will try to search first of all. The idea is not always to pick up the correct one, because that was our make-based approach, where we have done that.
Krish Naik: But by generating multiple wrong answers, you can actually reach your correct answer. So it's a step-by-step. Let's start with something wrong, okay? Then, slowly, slowly, it will improve.
Krish Naik: Okay? That is the idea, it will be based on scores, correct?
Krish Naik: It will be based on your similarity scores, as simple as that.
Krish Naik: Now, this is the example later on when I'll be showing you… more examples will be there from IDProspect, when I'll be talking about the main research paper, which was written by Gai. Okay? Don't worry, next week I'll be talking about that, but this is the high-level approach.
Krish Naik: The idea was to discuss the high-level approach. Okay, this is where it comes. Arun is the system searches for the vector database for real documents that are semantically similar to this fake answer, rather than the original question.
Krish Naik: Yes, correct. Because based on the original question, your hypothetical document was created.
Krish Naik: Based on that document.
Krish Naik: you have created hypothetical embeddings. Now, based on those hypothetical embeddings, you are performing the similarity search on top of the original document.
Krish Naik: Yes, ID is always used. Heidi, but ID, it means that if you're using ID, the latency of the rack drops down. That's the only thing.
Krish Naik: I feel that's, generally, like, Heidi, even for re-ranking, okay, whenever you are… because right now, as we are moving towards that advanced track, in advanced life, we have seen that, most of the times. If you are keeping these modules, for sure.
Krish Naik: Your retrievable accuracy will increase, but the speed will be much slower for that system.
Krish Naik: When do we use IDE? If there is no context window limitation, no such things like widget, we can use ID anytime. It's just a plug-and-play model.
Krish Naik: Okay?
Krish Naik: Yes, in industries, people are using ID, but it's not necessary. It's a module which can be plugged at any point of time.
Krish Naik: Is this part clear?
Krish Naik: So, this is one part of advanced. I told you, there are so many components. It's not necessary. You plug every component.
Krish Naik: I'm just talking about the one comp.
Krish Naik: Don't worry, okay? I just gave a high-level overview, and the next class, we'll be going through the research papers, so don't worry about that.
Krish Naik: The idea was to tell you how it is generated. Okay, so that's why I've given this particular example.
Krish Naik: All right.
Krish Naik: Now, JB is asking a hypothetical document generated based on the content of the query. No, there is no content around there. It's simply the user will ask the query based on that.
Krish Naik: Simple. User query.
Krish Naik: Okay. Is this part clear? There is nothing, that I am not looking into the original document, it's totally based on the question.
Krish Naik: Alright, now… Okay, now this has taken place now… alright, fine.
Krish Naik: As we have reached this part.
Krish Naik: Little bit, let's talk about that particular concept also.
Krish Naik: Okay, so the next concept…
Krish Naik: Because after this, we will just directly start our hybrid search part. So, a little bit about dense vectors and sparse vectors. How many of you know what is dense, what is sparse? Because generally, these things are taught in NLP. So, quickly let me know.
Krish Naik: Okay, most of you, no, no, no, no, no.
Krish Naik: Alright, fine.
Krish Naik: Aware of this, aware of this, okay? Alright.
Krish Naik: Alright.
Krish Naik: Vector database, Ravi, yes, vector databases. So, generally, let's talk a little bit about that, okay? A quick high level, I'm not going in-depth, because this is pure NLP basics.
Krish Naik: Now, whenever, we are talking about sparse, Okay.
Krish Naik: bars… Okay, so let's take dens.
Krish Naik: Yes, so whenever we are working with dents.
Krish Naik: The first thing, there will be low dimensions.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: They will be lower dimensions as compared to sparse. Okay, and where most of the values within that particular vector will be non-zero. Okay? Pretty much non-zero.
Krish Naik: And, whereas in this case of pass, this will be very high dimension.
Krish Naik: Okay? Not only high, I will say very high.
Krish Naik: Okay. And mostly zero.
Krish Naik: Okay. Now, this is, common ones.
Krish Naik: Now, with respect to dense vectors, generally, what is the dimension? I have seen that people are working with, 128 till, like, 409 sets.
Krish Naik: Based on current research that I am telling. Okay, now this is for your dens. Similarly for sparse, when I'm talking about.
Krish Naik: Sparse dimension, generally in hybrid search in the rag that we'll be using. It will be starting from 10,000,
Krish Naik: 250,000.
Krish Naik: Okay, so really, they are at very, very high dimension. Now, coming to dense, a few common examples.
Krish Naik: Anybody can tell me, with respect to tennis, what are the common examples?
Krish Naik: Generally, we'll be using some type of neural network, so, something like Word2Vec.
Krish Naik: is a common one. Then you have, from Stanford NLP, you have GLOVE. Then, you have BERT…
Krish Naik: Okay? Then, probably your OpenAI, any type of embeddings that you are currently working with.
Krish Naik: Because in this course, till now, we have only worked with, tense embeddings.
Krish Naik: Okay, based on transformers, simply, if I'm talking with respect to images also, so probably with respect to CNN-based or VIT-based embeddings. So, these are common sources.
Krish Naik: Okay, so at any point of time, you can use this type of algorithms, and you can use
Krish Naik: Digmajay is telling Bo, no, not back off words. Guys, whoever is told back off words.
Krish Naik: Not for backup work. Okay? Now, generally, these type of neural network-based, whenever you are trying to, do… what are the major advantages whenever you are doing?
Krish Naik: for this approach.
Krish Naik: Advantages of dense.
Krish Naik: Quickly tell me.
Krish Naik: The core thing, because everything started from the year close to 2017, with respect to tense vectors major. One is strong semantic understanding.
Krish Naik: This is a main idea. Okay, so that's why this becomes really good for similarity search.
Krish Naik: Okay, and these two are the major factors, and initially, if you start your NLP journey, once you start learning the first algorithm with respect to this, you will be learning what to vet. Another, a neural network. And the second one, probably, will be looking into glove.
Krish Naik: Okay? No, nothing with respect to reach metadata and other things. Less spacious, that you can say, much more compact.
Krish Naik: This I can see, because they are having lesser dimension. So, for sure, they will compact. We were told, I think.
Krish Naik: Sankith, yes. That part is correct. They will be having much more compact storage. Okay, so…
Krish Naik: Just because, lesser numbers.
Krish Naik: Now the question, what are the disadvantages in this one, guys?
Krish Naik: The major disadvantages is we cannot understand anything.
Krish Naik: That is the main disadvantage that I feel, so I will keep something, like, hard to interpret.
Krish Naik: It means that zero explainability, there is no explainability.
Krish Naik: You are not explaining one this thing.
Krish Naik: Okay. And, generally, in these cases, like, for example, if you're working with Bird, Globe, this will take much more computational power to generate these things. Okay, so, like, costly to compute.
Krish Naik: Okay, I think I've given you enough high-level overview with respect to tensile. This part clear for everyone? Can I move to Sparks quickly?
Krish Naik: Yes, let me know, guys, quickly.
Krish Naik: No, right, let's, finally a little bit about the sparse part.
Krish Naik: So, for your sparse.
Krish Naik: Now, what are the algorithms that you have learned for sparselling?
Krish Naik: One of the most common ones, so let's talk about the algos here.
Krish Naik: B-O-W.
Krish Naik: Backup words.
Krish Naik: Okay? Any other algorithm?
Krish Naik: TFIDF.
Krish Naik: Alright, even, like, in… Any other?
Krish Naik: One hot encoding.
Krish Naik: Why not encoding is really… okay, count vectorize are correct. Okay, yes, somebody is studying BM25.
Krish Naik: Correct
Krish Naik: Okay? Now, these are the common algorithms.
Krish Naik: Now, with respect to these algorithms.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, it's very, very high dimension.
Krish Naik: Okay, so that's why the first problem already I pulled before, so I won't get right here. Very high dimensional, they will have a lot of zeros. And why zeros? Why many zeros?
Krish Naik: Why many zeros comes into this type of algorithms?
Krish Naik: Why the occurrence of zeros?
Krish Naik: Biology is telling… because sparse, why sparse?
Krish Naik: sparse meals having zeros. You can't say having mostly zeros is called sparse. It's just the English meaning of having zeros.
Krish Naik: Because in this type of algorithms, you have the concept of the vocabulary size.
Krish Naik: I think… please go through this concept at least, okay, just for a rewind. Okay, you have a concept of vocabulary size.
Krish Naik: Anybody remember? Vocabulary size, for example, how many unique words?
Krish Naik: Yes, JV tools spread over the existing unique words. That becomes your vocabulary.
Krish Naik: Okay, because every word only be occurring in every sentence.
Krish Naik: Can I say that every word won't be occurring in every sentence? So for sure, if it is not occurring, there will be 000. As simple as that. Okay, based on the vocabulary size that I have. So that's why these are pretty much high dimensions. And
Krish Naik: Really, like, for… these are very cheap to compute. This is really cheap computation. You can calculate it directly in your system.
Krish Naik: Okay, so generally, you have a package, there is a package called as fast embed.
Krish Naik: So, using the fast embed package, you can actually do those things.
Krish Naik: Okay, and this is, really good for exact matching.
Krish Naik: The exact keyword-based matching for these type of algorithms really works very much good.
Krish Naik: Okay, so generally, what are the use cases, like keyword search, filtering, scoring, or hybrid retrieval? Okay, so that's why. Finally, these two things we will try to combine. My, sparse
Krish Naik: plus dense, Okay. When you try to combine, this will become your hybrid.
Krish Naik: So, both the vectors that can be kept. So, remember, whenever you are working with hybrid waste systems, so generally your, cost increases. So, from the cost perspective, also, I'm telling you, it means that you'll be saving somewhere. For example, if you're using quadrant.
Krish Naik: And I say that the number of vectors will increase? Because most organizations charge based on the number of vectors.
Krish Naik: Okay, and it's really the dimension of these sparse vectors are really, really big. So I told you the ranges come from 10,000 to 50,000.
Krish Naik: Okay, so somewhere in between, I can test it out around 25,000 or 30,000. So it's not really necessary that if you are going with higher dimensions, first sparse, you will get better results. There is no such concept behind that.
Krish Naik: Okay? But at least somewhere around 15,000 to $20,000, that will be your good start to go.
Krish Naik: Arun, that is not part of… metadata filtering is totally different.
Krish Naik: Okay, that comes under hybrid search. Sorry, that comes under your 10 search. That is not part of your sparse vectors.
Krish Naik: All right, now this part, we have gone through. Now let's get back, because few things we have…
Krish Naik: Dropped here, now let's get back here.
Krish Naik: We will continue the discussion with the notebooks. I think we have passed that. So, little bit idea I thought about giving about Heidi and others.
Krish Naik: Screens… I think this is Rextop 2.
Krish Naik: All right. So, now, this RRF algorithm, okay? Now, what is the purpose of use… this RRF algorithm? So, if you want to combine both
Krish Naik: Parse?
Krish Naik: plus dense. It means that you have to do a combine of those two vectors. Once is your sparse vector, one is your dense vector.
Krish Naik: So, in those cases, RRF comes, so reciprocal rank vision is the algorithm through which you will be merging your tens and your sparse vector search.
Krish Naik: So that's why… that is the main purpose of reciprocal VLAN.
Krish Naik: Okay? So I think I'll be talking about reciprocal RRF in the next class.
Krish Naik: So, finally… so, first of all, here I have defined… so I've given you quite a high-level overview, at least for this. Later on, we'll be diving into this concept.
Krish Naik: Can you give one example of sparse vector search? Simple, backup words, Dinesh.
Krish Naik: Alright, now, Let's try to initialize my retriever.
Krish Naik: Today's class is difficult. Yes, the topics are difficult, the implementation is difficult, so it will be difficult. If you're not good with basics.
Krish Naik: I know, like, it will be a problem with two.
Krish Naik: Alright, now, see, so previously I've defined my two retrievers, and now, based on that, I have prepared my query fusion retriever, where I'll be passing both the retrievers, and finally.
Krish Naik: The similarity result that I'll be looking into. Now, number of queries that should be generated, so generate one query variant only. Now, this is for ID. Then comes your RRF, so this is basically the approach through which we do the merging of the results of Sparks
Krish Naik: And this.
Krish Naik: Okay? Now, this concept I'll be talking about, in the next class, because right now I've just given you very, very…
Krish Naik: high-level overview of hybrid search. Next class, we will go much more deeper.
Krish Naik: Even there is another algorithm also, RSF. Okay, now this is RF, there is an alternate algorithm, which we don't use, like, after 2023, very less people are using. We immediately… we have shifted towards, RRF.
Krish Naik: So let me just do the initialization of the retriever, and now I'll be just…
Krish Naik: Looking into the queries, okay? Now, this is my query that I have passed. What are the key innovations in Word? Okay, now this is… now let's try to look, because my query is ready, I need to pass it to my retriever. Here, I have passed it.
Krish Naik: And this is my infusion notes.
Krish Naik: Okay, and based on that, I can say that, okay, I got the results. Now, really, what are the key innovations in the board? Title, port, so this is the first level.
Krish Naik: In, because this is the abstract part here, we don't have any sections. So this is the first mood-level intuition, because, why? This is key level, key word matching, so that's why birth to bird. So that's why we got this particular result here.
Krish Naik: Then comes something with respect to the section, and very specifically an introduction. Again, both got repeated.
Krish Naik: Then, finally, with the section, with respect to fine-tuning, I got some results, but all the scores are blue. Really, I cannot say directly the results are very, very good.
Krish Naik: But, the results which have been written, because top 5 result, finally it is switching to the attention is all you need part, but I feel in every part, the scores are… so somehow I feel on top of the original data, I don't have enough data, or the quality of the data that I provided.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, this is one approach where I mixed a little bit of ID with hybrid search.
Krish Naik: Okay, so this is where your query fusion, why the name fusion comes? Because here we are performing an RRF-based operation.
Krish Naik: Okay, the reciprocal.
Krish Naik: rank fusion. So that's why it's referred to as the fusion retreat.
Krish Naik: Yes, all the scores are low, so really, anything, like, 0.03, this is a very bad score. We will not accept none of the results.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: Because based on the results that I have, I feel all the results are really new.
Krish Naik: Now, somewhere, probably, I can change… okay, so probably, you can play with the parameters from here. You can increase this to probably, let's make it 8, let's make it 5.
Krish Naik: Okay? So, the idea is, during recall, you can lower the similarity score, but during precision, the idea is to keep it. Number of queries, let me make it 2. Similarity, let me make it 3. Okay?
Krish Naik: And right now, based on the async operation, let me see… I'm not using any async, that's why we have kept it false.
Krish Naik: Two questions, so it will take more time as compared to one question.
Krish Naik: anywhere north of when we are defining, by default, the Fusion Retriever uses ID. That's why you very specifically mentioned about it.
Krish Naik: Custom ID implementation, I'll be showing. But for now, can you see that this is taking a lot of time?
Krish Naik: But it should not take so much time, Oscar.
Krish Naik: Let's see.
Krish Naik: I have not done any error handling.
Krish Naik: It should not take 40 seconds, I don't know why it's taking.
Krish Naik: do, probably I need to restart the notebook, I think. It worksbooks and mine.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, it took around 1 minute, okay, just for those 3 results, and right now, based on that, I can see everywhere, it has picked up wherever there is birth and birth and birth and birth. So, majorly, all the birth-based documents directly based on the keyword search, it has picked up, and nothing new. In your case, it took 0.7 seconds.
Krish Naik: really, like, if I try to reinitialize, Depends upon system to system.
Krish Naik: But, this case, it's faster. It means once the execution is done, probably through Gatch8 is accessing.
Krish Naik: Okay, so this time it's much faster. But again, I feel that the results are not really good. Okay, if you really look into your text notes, because now this is my actual data.
Krish Naik: Now, through this data, when I actually try to look into my core content.
Krish Naik: Okay, so somehow, in the poor content with respect to features.
Krish Naik: Somehow I can say lesser things are much…
Krish Naik: Available here, because this is a total document.
Krish Naik: And from this particular document, you just need to focus on these
Krish Naik: The actual content will be based on 3 only.
Krish Naik: Because one is the top-level node. The top-level node doesn't have those benefits or features. That's the actual answer that I'm looking for.
Krish Naik: But a few things I can see here that can actually be presented, but, really.
Krish Naik: I cannot see a lot of benefits.
Krish Naik: Alright, get on 5 users. The idea was to show you this implementation of Query Fusion, and really, sometimes you might use it, and sometimes you might not.
Krish Naik: And, later on, I'll be showing you. So, generally, we don't combine everything in one shot. Our core implementation will be much more simpler. It means that we'll be doing an implementation of Heidi separately, we will be doing an implementation, so every implementation, we'll be keeping it separate.
Krish Naik: Here, everything gets happened in one shot, but in, like, Saturday class, I will try to break that thing. In Lansion, directly, this is available, so a similar example in Lansion also I will show, but the idea is to break this up, not to make this thing happen in one shot.
Krish Naik: Generally, in production, when you are working, you should have that feature that whenever you are making that API call, during that API call, you should have all these settings. It means that, when you are making the retrieval, do you want ID to be switched on?
Krish Naik: a simple parameter. Within your API body, in your request body, you should have that.
Krish Naik: Okay, so within the JSON, generally, you keep that ID, true or false, something like that you will be keeping. Do you want a hybrid search? Yes or no. Okay, so similarly. So all those things should be there within your request body, whenever you are working with this, because your retrieval speed will increase.
Krish Naik: Okay, and sometimes, if your neighbor app falls, then only, by default, we enable those parameters.
Krish Naik: Alright.
Krish Naik: Now, this was a few things, okay, and a little bit about the re-ranking, the RRF fusion part that we'll be talking about in the next class, don't worry.
Krish Naik: Now, this is a custom retriever implementation. Now, you might work with a custom retriever. We generally don't work a lot. Here, a simple example with archive that we are taking into account.
Krish Naik: Now, you can create your custom retriever, the same option was available in Langchen also. Okay, now this, the idea is to, first of all, get the base retriever.
Krish Naik: Through Base Retriever, you will be creating your own custom retriever. So, this is your custom retriever class that I have created, which is a Citation Booster Retriever.
Krish Naik: Okay, now this retriever, if you look into the core properties, yes, I will be taking… that's why inheriting the properties that I have done. Citation width, now this is a parameter. Later on, I'll be calling, so when I'll be making the use of this class, I'll be passing. This is a weightage for every citation that I can pass.
Krish Naik: Now, here we have initialized, simple, the base retriever and the citation grid.
Krish Naik: So, why the citation rate we have passed? So, generally, whenever you are searching about research papers, in how many places that research paper has been placed in citations?
Krish Naik: I think everybody knows the meaning of citations.
Krish Naik: A single research paper, attention is all you need. That research paper might have more than 30,000 or 40,000 citations.
Krish Naik: Okay, so that's why the weightage to citations that we are providing.
Krish Naik: Okay, so simply two things, and the core thing with respect to super passing that as init.
Krish Naik: Now, then coming to step retrieve, so this is the part. Now, in this custom retriever, you will see that, first of all, I am initializing my base retriever.
Krish Naik: and query bundle. This query bundle is basically a list of modes with school.
Krish Naik: Okay, it means that whenever you will perform, the output of this retriever will be a list of nodes. It means that this is the written type of Lama Intense.
Krish Naik: So that's why mode risk score has specifically been mentioned.
Krish Naik: And, as you can see here, so the first step is the retrieval part, then we have this, re-ranking operation. Okay, so through max… okay, so let me just close this one here.
Krish Naik: Node.metadata get citations. Okay, so for node in every node, the idea is to access every node.
Krish Naik: And from there, we'll be getting the citations one by one, and that information will be keeping it in metadata. The idea is to combine the similarity score with the citation boost. Now, this citation boost parameter, you'll be passing in from here. So, with this, your actual similarity score will be added to provide you the finding boost.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, generally, this implementation, I've just taken a sample from the official documentation only. We don't work with such custom retrievers, because in some cases, it might be useful, but really, I've never
Krish Naik: created a custom retriever, but I have worked with Fusion Retrievers a lot.
Krish Naik: So this is one example, just to show you that, yes, this can also be done, where you can combine multiple things.
Krish Naik: But you have to understand the cold retrieval happens with your base retrieval. Now, whenever you're… you are creating any retrieval, you have to always use the base retrieval technique, which is actually… which is actually a vector retrieval only.
Krish Naik: Now, on top of that, you will be performing, like, whatever operations. Here, only I've kept revanking.
Krish Naik: But if you want to keep some other operations, you can keep here.
Krish Naik: few fusion techniques also, you can add it here. So, it's totally up to you, because this is a custom retriever, so whatever the things that you want to pass, you want to pass ID separately, you can do that.
Krish Naik: you know, all those things. It means that during your retrieval, if you want everything to be activated in one shot, it means that, okay, during my retrieval, I want Heidi to be on, hybrid search to be on, everything to be on, so every… all type of functions keep it here. So in that way, you can actually create it.
Krish Naik: Post-retriever… yes, you can add all your post-retriever operations.
Krish Naik: Okay, so somehow, like, if you feel that in one shot, if you want to do, otherwise try to break things. So this was a simple example that we have taken for this one.
Krish Naik: Okay, so I think… Does… One, let's take… Okay, and based on that.
Krish Naik: Okay, and here, during this particular, call of this, retriever, the citation retriever, here I am passing the default weightage as 0.3.
Krish Naik: Okay, now this will be even added with your retrieval. So finally, based on the query that I am passing, machine learning models.
Krish Naik: Okay, so I can see some information that I'm getting from the base retriever.
Krish Naik: So, these are the results from the base retriever. Okay, and really, if I look into the results, because I'm applying every data on top for a hierarchical data, but it is not necessary that for Fusion or for these type of retrievers, every time you have to use hierarchical data only. Here, you can pass your own simple data also.
Krish Naik: This, I want to make clear for everyone. In these examples, I am using hierarchical data, but it is not relevant here. It means that you can pass your normal data.
Krish Naik: Because of that, we are getting lower scores.
Krish Naik: Am I making sense to everyone? This is the type of data, because of that, I'm getting scored. It's not the algorithm.
Krish Naik: If you try to pick up a simple PDF and try to process it through this, you will get better results. But right now, I'm not reading a separate PDF. I'm just using my own hierarchical data, which is not suitable for this type of purpose.
Krish Naik: Alright, now really, if you look into the base retrieval scores, okay, so scores 0.37, 0.36, and 0.35. After applying, citation boost rate retriever, even my scores has got down. So, simply, I can say that in this particular situation, it is really not required.
Krish Naik: Okay, I can say my base retriever is performing much better as compared to the citation.
Krish Naik: So the idea was to show you is not that when I teach you a technique, that technique will work every time.
Krish Naik: Okay, so the idea was to show you an example.
Krish Naik: And now these are some custom implementations, so, like.
Krish Naik: Pretty much, you will be using very, very less.
Krish Naik: Like, it's only for specialized needs only.
Krish Naik: Okay, so majorly, okay. Now, a little bit about Heidi, as we have talked today. So, this is the final thing, I think, today we'll be discussing. I don't want to discuss anything more, already a few people attended.
Krish Naik: it has become hard, so only this notebook. This notebook, probably the hybrid search and the re-racking, we'll be discussing in the next class.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, there is a hydride transform, so in Llama Index, directly, this is available.
Krish Naik: Okay, so here you can pass, like, include original is equal to true, or you can make it false also. The idea was that whether you want to use the original documents or not, to create that. So, you can pass it false, or you can make it true. By default, it's the true version, so…
Krish Naik: I will be passing and making it as the default ones.
Krish Naik: Okay, so by default, you can see the Boolean version within the class is referred to as 2.
Krish Naik: Now, this is a class. Now, on top of this class, the fusion index that previously it was created. If you remember, we had a Fusion Index.
Krish Naik: Somewhere, I think.
Krish Naik: Previously, okay, this fusion query with your Fusion index somewhere, this one.
Krish Naik: Okay? Alright, now I'll be using this fusion index directly on top of this.
Krish Naik: Later on, you can change the index, I think everybody understands that part. Okay, so first of all, this is the initialization of IDE, then whatever is your query engine. So on top of that index, you can perform a query, you can look into
Krish Naik: this particular. Now, this is purely based query engine. Now, let's try to transform this by adding ID. So, for that, you have a separate query engine, which is called a transform query engine, where you can pass ID directly.
Krish Naik: Now, what type of transformations you want to do? So, ID is basically a query transformation technique. There are other techniques also that we'll be talking about, like query decomposition and other things, but this is one of the examples of query transformation. So, where specifically I have added ID.
Krish Naik: Okay, now let me just pause this.
Krish Naik: Okay, so right now, the main,
Krish Naik: ID query engine initialization that I have done, and to that, I have passed my base query engine, and what type of transformation that already I have defined right here.
Krish Naik: Now, in the next step, the test query with the standard retrieval, let's try to look.
Krish Naik: So, here, the ID query that I have, so what are the limitations of RNN? Okay, now, the standard query engine, I can initialize it on top of that. So, I'm past a query. I'm looking into the original one, as well as the default one.
Krish Naik: Now, if you directly, look into the standard query, it will be processed much faster as compared to Hyde. For example, simply let's, comment this, TFAP code, okay?
Krish Naik: Command, question mark, yes. So, first of all, let's start to look how this response is coming.
Krish Naik: the standard one. Can you see? This is much faster, like, 1.8 seconds it took?
Krish Naik: Okay, and somehow the response that is coming, recurrent networks are inherently sequential, which means they cannot be parallelized, this limitation effect. So somehow I can say that, yes, I'm getting the result. Now, let's try to switch on this one.
Krish Naik: Now, somehow, this will be, like, as I have told the variant gene.
Krish Naik: First, it will generate the hypothetical cancer, then it will retrieve. So, little bit, it will take more time. So, that's why I'm telling you, whenever you add Heidi to the system, it means that it will take more time to get your final result.
Krish Naik: And probably, if you look into, in this case, the result is very similar, because directly from the document that it is picking up, and this limitation affects and passes it through the sequence.
Krish Naik: Okay, so if you really look into, do you feel that, somehow it has changed? If you really look into few things, so probably here, efficiency and speed in processing sequences, your AND and speed has been removed.
Krish Naik: In the hypothetical part.
Krish Naik: Okay, and rest of the piece of code is same. So, if you really look into, I can say that yes, some amount of transformation through the query engine that has been taken place.
Krish Naik: Always remember, whenever you are working with hypothetical embeddings, it means that it will take much more time.
Krish Naik: Now, this is the first example in our course that we have taken for a query transformation.
Krish Naik: Okay?
Krish Naik: let's skip it till this point only. Rest of the things we'll be discussing in the next class, where we will start our hybrid search and rev ranking, because a lot of theory will be discussing this, dense vectors and sparse vector you guys already know. BM25, how many of you have learned BM25 algorithm in NLP?
Krish Naik: Yes, please let me know. BM25? Okay, most people are blunt. Okay, so in simple terms, I can say that if you've learned TF IDF, that is upgraded version.
Krish Naik: Like, the VM25 is basically the upgraded version of DFI, DF algorithm.
Krish Naik: So, we'll be, first of all, looking into the implementations and few concepts. The idea is how to do that merge of both the vectors. So, there comes the concept of RRF. For that RRF concept, first we will dive into it through the next class.
Krish Naik: So, implement hybrid search combining semantics. So, this implementation goes through RF only.
Krish Naik: Then for, getting hybrid score fusions, the alpha parameter is there within hybrid search, we'll be talking about that. And finally, coming to RAND. So, Cohar is based on APIs, okay?
Krish Naik: Now, how many of you have access to AWS Bedrock? You can access Kuhar embeddings through that also, or if you want Kuhar embeddings, because this is a paid service, guys.
Krish Naik: Okay, now, this is one of the majorly used redraki in the market.
Krish Naik: Otherwise, you can use something free. Like, cross and porters are there, freely from Hugging Face, that part also you can do. I've already shared the notebook, so before that, just be sure you test out the cells by yourself.
Krish Naik: I think for Kuhar, this part is here. So you can skip this part, because you need a Kuhar API key, but at least, you can do the testing with the default one. You can see here, MS Marco Mini, so this is one of the famous re-ranking models, which is totally free, that you can work with.
Krish Naik: Okay, there are heavier models also. Now, this is a lighter version.
Krish Naik: So, I think few things in the next class, then we will start with our hybrid search. And even that Heidi research paper also I'll be talking about, the research paper by Gaio.
Krish Naik: Alright, so I think I'm done, guys. Okay, so… and start taking. ESID is a query transformation technique. One of the examples, there are other things also that we'll be talking about.
Krish Naik: And this is during the retrieval, yes. It means that somebody will ask the question, then the retrieval process will start. So, in that process only. So, yes, during the retrieval, Heidi comes into the picture.
Krish Naik: Oh, ho, alright.
Krish Naik: Now, this content is a bit heavy, so just think about in the next 3 to 4 classes, at least for the next week and after that, little bit things will be heavy. Because once you have caused the heavy part, it will be all about implementation.
Krish Naik: in Haystack, because from Llama Index, once we switch to Haystack, and I'll be teaching you Haystack probably, I think.
Krish Naik: as, like, after this, in haystack, everything will be a function call. So there, you won't see anything. What is going behind the scenes. Everything is function call in haystack.
Krish Naik: So, if you have the fundamentals correct, quickly you can switch to it.
Krish Naik: Re-ranking, I have not taught Mama, don't worry, I will teach re-ranking. Till now, I have not taught re-ranking. Little bit, only today, I have told about Heidi and, sparse vector and delvector. So, don't worry.
Krish Naik: Alright, let me start taking the questions. So, Rajat, Mitesh, Devijay, They bought.
Krish Naik: Okay, a few people I've unmuted, so one by one.
Mitesh Shah: Yeah, hi, Medisha.
Krish Naik: So, I was getting, during the chonky part of it, when we were talking about the,
Mitesh Shah: When a slumber chunker, right? Before Slumber Chunker, I was getting that index out of, index issue.
Krish Naik: Alright, show me, because even… just show me, I need to check that implementation cost.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, hi, Paul.
Krish Naik: Yes?
Rajat Khanna: Yes. So, I have two questions. One is related to the chunky, that you are teaching. So, previously that we were building naive racks, so we just, directly used LLMs for the chunking and embedding and, creating, vector DB.
Rajat Khanna: So, it… is it necessary, or it is,
Rajat Khanna: You can say a good approach to use Chonky, or the LLMs that are available, different models, that will be fine.
Krish Naik: See, first of all, the question that you asked, why LLMs? First of all, keep that separate. Okay. You can use the cool chunking from Lama Index, or for LangChain, that is one option. Otherwise, move to Chonky. Actually, what happened? Chonky has an enterprise version also, where directly you can upload your products using APIs, you can make everything automated.
Krish Naik: Okay, so that's why. So I feel that Chunky is good, but most of the times, like, based on the documents, you have to do the research, like, which chunker, for which document type you need to. That's…
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Rajat Khanna: And.
Krish Naik: Taza is asking just wait, Fusion Retriever is also there in Langchain. In Langchain, the name is different. Explicitly, it's not called Fusion Retriever. There, you will be having the name Ensemble Retriever, more Taza.
Krish Naik: That's it?
Krish Naik: Yes, Ted.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, and second question is, like, I'm only part of this, RAG class, so the topics that you have teached today, so I have… means not down, because I don't have much, deep knowledge into that.
Rajat Khanna: So, within this week, so if I'll prepare all these things, will the next Saturday class will not go above our head.
Krish Naik: No, no, see, whatever I told, you might not know about backup hours, whatnot, including those things. It will take maximum 30 minutes. Set for 30 minutes and go through this. Those techniques, even in class, like, quickly, those are very, very easy concepts.
Rajat Khanna: It's not very, very hot.
Krish Naik: Yeah, I need to…
Digvijay: Didn't we?
Rajat Khanna: I do not have that idea as well, so I'll go through those concepts as well.
Krish Naik: These are very old techniques, it means that these are 1980s people I've been working with. Anything that I've taken, probably it might take time for you for more, what to wear glove.
Krish Naik: In what two algorithms are there, the skipgram, okay, and the CPOW. That part is important, you can focus on even in interviews, sometimes the questions are asked, I think.
Krish Naik: Okay, that is the only thing. Glove, don't focus a lot, because that project by Christopher Manning, because I've been following that project back from 2016. So, don't go through Glove. Glove is not so much important. Directly, we'll be having glove models if you check their website.
Krish Naik: Because the core implementation was based on Java only, so probably it will be harder for you to don't… but just have a look into what to make only.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, that's… thank you.
Krish Naik: Okay, so what I was telling you it is.
deba: Working novel, can you share? Alright.
deba: Whoever isn't the panelist, please share, Mitesh. You are there, Mitesh, what you are waiting for.
deba: Hi, Paul. Like, I just had a question, like, when do we use hybrid search?
Digvijay: Any particular use cases?
Krish Naik: No, no. You can use always hybrid search. Why?
Digvijay: fee.
Krish Naik: If you want keyword matching support, sometimes it's necessary. Just think about your semantic search fit.
Digvijay: Hmm.
Krish Naik: Okay, and you need. Then, probably, you might look for an algorithm which will help you to provide keyword search.
Krish Naik: Simple. T-word means text-based search. If my hybrid search fails, then can I say that there will be a fallback to keyword searching?
Digvijay: I got it. Paul, let's say a FAQ document of a company is there, and it contains tables as well as images. So, can we implement a hybrid search in this scenario?
Krish Naik: Now, if you can create, there is no restriction, because even if you have a table, that table data will be later on based on text only, then those texts will be converted in… probably those tables will be converted in the CSV format, like to a table chunker, like in Chonky, you have.
Krish Naik: through that, then again embed it through, yes. Now, for images, it will be different.
Krish Naik: If you have images, now, for those images, you have to take care, because you have to create, now, different multimodal embeddings.
Krish Naik: For that, you need a different embedding mode. But yes, you can, create some captions. It means that at least can you say that, okay, in your case, what is the representation of that image within your application?
Krish Naik: That caption, if you pass it, then at least it will save that information.
Digvijay: Okay, so we have to do multiple approaches. First, we have to do parsing, and then we have to…
Krish Naik: This is multimodal parsing. It means that you need to handle text as well as images, as you mentioned. That will be our, I think, fourth project, multimodal track.
Digvijay: Okay, okay, okay, okay, yeah, I understood. So, Paul, like, if we implement hybrid search, will the latency be more, or…
Krish Naik: Yes, the latency will be more for sure. See, once you are performing a dense vector search, then you'll be performing a sparse. But sparse vector search won't take up very long, so that's why it's recommended. I recommend
Krish Naik: doing a hybrid search, but I don't always recommend working with high D.
Krish Naik: Okay, there will be other things also, like re-ranking. R-ranking takes more time.
Krish Naik: Okay, because it totally depends upon what type of model you are using, so it takes more time. So, for sure, when in each, when you add those components, just think about 3 seconds, 4 seconds more.
Digvijay: Oh, dear.
Digvijay: Okay.
Digvijay: Okay, yeah, that's alright.
deba: Have a… yeah. Thank you.
deba: Alright.
Mitesh Shah: screen.
deba: Yes, show me now. Yeah, so basically, I'm just going to the basic.
Mitesh Shah: version of Neural Chunker, added this particular pa- particular line with 2,000, characters.
Mitesh Shah: did a chunk on it. On the chunk itself, this line, I'm getting index out of range itself.
Krish Naik: Alright, just wait, let me just go back to my notebook once.
Krish Naik: Quickly, let me just, look into that.
Krish Naik: Neural Chunker. I think one lane is, let's see what… just wait.
Krish Naik: Just, neural chunk, sample text.
Krish Naik: Alright, now this is your sample text that you have provided.
Mitesh Shah: Yes.
Krish Naik: neural chunker.chunk, you are passing the sample test, that particular line you have added. Rest, okay, display part, you have, okay, fine, you have commented, that is not required. So, it's telling a red line, so neural…
Krish Naik: Chunks is equal to neural chunker dot.
Krish Naik: Or junk?
Krish Naik: neural chunk or torch chunk, then you are passing the sample test. Yes, this is correct.
Mitesh Shah: Index out of range itself.
Krish Naik: Okay… Try to reload the document, try to assume… I just did. Okay, just did.
Mitesh Shah: First of all, show me that research paper text. Try to print it out in a…
Mitesh Shah: I did, this one.
Krish Naik: Yes, that research paper, just print it out in a name set.
Krish Naik: Just to show that.
Mitesh Shah: Okay.
Krish Naik: Just print out the original information.
Krish Naik: Okay, now this original information, only the research paper part. Research paper, yes. Now, at the indexer.
Mitesh Shah: Sorry, Ed?
Krish Naik: The index also, with 2000…
Krish Naik: Here you have added that, you are getting this also, fine. Now, here you have added the print text, alright, neural terms. Can you pass the sample, paper text.
Krish Naik: Research paper takes all right. Yes, this looks good to me. There is nothing to change in this point.
Krish Naik: Intex staling. Try to… if you are trying to lower the value, then also you are getting the same error.
Mitesh Shah: Yep.
Krish Naik: I tried with 20 as well.
Krish Naik: And etc.
Krish Naik: Because 20, shh, you have tried. Change the minimum characters per jump, reduce it to 400.
Krish Naik: Okay, and… And check.
Krish Naik: Every time it's telling me, I'm feeling that,
Krish Naik: Some other variable is getting loaded or marked.
Krish Naik: Because the error is coming, scroll down, index out of range himself.
Krish Naik: It simply means the document is showing the error.
Krish Naik: We don't have changed to a spot.
Krish Naik: Increase… make that $222,000, don't use 20.
Krish Naik: Yes.
Krish Naik: Here, also, it's failing.
Krish Naik: Oh, really? Because 2,000 characters with 400, I know at least 5 chunks will be, based on the characters.
Krish Naik: So, those are really minimum characters. Based on that, I have passed.
Krish Naik: Neural chunker with a red line.
Mitesh Shah: No, that's an issue, that's not an issue, it's a Pyntic issue with my…
Krish Naik: No, no, no, no. No, no, no. Import is fine. I can see the… in line number 14 only it's free.
Krish Naik: Really? Like, it's the same piece of code.
Krish Naik: Oh, how it is not.
Krish Naik: Try to take this implementation in a new notebook.
Mitesh Shah: I bet.
Krish Naik: Only this part. Okay, just try to do that.
Krish Naik: Once.
deba: Sometimes in collab also.
deba: Device map, it's not a device map error, so I don't think that part, by default… I probably will do it, and I will come back to you, because I think, if I change it to Python, it would… it might work.
deba: Try that, okay. I think so, this neural chunker that I implemented, installed, right, through Pub, might have an issue. I'm not sure.
deba: Alright, have a check on that. I did, on Git, on one of the LLMs, I started searching for it, and then they said, please reinstall the neural junk.
deba: Alright.
deba: I will check. Okay. Thank you. Yeah, Paul, can I… But my question?
deba: Yes, yes, please go ahead. Okay, so I have, two, three questions. First thing is, you talked about this, chunky Enterprise version. So in this enterprise version, if we upload any document, is chunky giving the, strategy? How exactly the chunking and embedding has to be done? No, that is automated. They want it automated.
deba: Okay.
deba: Okay, thanks. Second question is, you told that, maybe in the structure of hierarchical structure implementation, for, for the chunking, right? For the JSON structure, is it a must, if I'm dealing with a, very deep-nested JSON, where we have to consider the hierarchy things, actually?
deba: Yes, in those cases. In my case, I have taken only two levels of nested, and probably in your case, you might work with 3 level or 4 level of nested.
deba: Okay. So, it makes your search much more optimized. That's why I feel that it is important. Okay. So the overlap might not help always, right? If I put overlap by 20%, that probably not give, you know, that accuracy.
deba: Here, overlap doesn't matter only, no, just think.
deba: there will be key-value pairs. Now, in key-value pairs, it's not necessary that you are always getting that, because one is… one unit is different for one key. That can be for different. So, here, really, that overlap doesn't matter to me.
deba: Yeah, that's correct.
deba: Yeah.
deba: Because they have totally different meanings, because they come under different keys only. Yeah, yes.
deba: Understood, yeah. And last question, it's a little out of the box. As of now, we are, we are learning still the text embedding. There is a concept, text-to-SQL, right? Is that totally a different concept, or it would also, gets implemented in a similar line, like the way?
deba: It's a similar implementation, only generally in text-to-SQL, you'll be looking into the tables.
deba: Now, from each table, you will be attaching that header with each row. You will pick up each row, then you will perform an embedding-based operation.
deba: That's the strategy. So it's pretty much similar in that.
deba: So, you will take any example in upcoming classes? Next project, no. In the next project only, I'll be talking about Texas. Oh, okay, okay, okay.
deba: Thank you so much.
deba: Alright, then.
Krish Naik: You can look into the source code also.
deba: So, it is available in Magit.
deba: Yeah, sure. Sure.
Krish Naik: All the right then comes ambush.
Krish Naik: Aruna, the color of the hand is really… dark. These usually light colors.
Krish Naik: Yes, I'm Butch.
ambuj sharma: Hey.
ambuj sharma: No.
ambuj sharma: Hello, Paul. So, I just have a question… two… two questions I have. One is, I have doc… I have PDFs and… and docs.
Krish Naik: I've worked with me?
ambuj sharma: PDFs?
ambuj sharma: Right? It went with text and images, right?
ambuj sharma: And for the images, I just need the captions, just to maintain the context.
Krish Naik: Yes.
ambuj sharma: Right, so I just need to know that what kind of architecture pattern that we can use, right? Because we have learned multiple frameworks, right, and multiple ways to.
Krish Naik: Stick to Docklings. Doclinks will help you out. Stick to Docklings, it will do that.
ambuj sharma: Okay, so if I say that docklink for parsing, right, and then lama index for chunking and indexing.
ambuj sharma: Using this sentence chunker, and then…
Krish Naik: You can use Llama Index as well as LanChain. Both things can be achieved.
ambuj sharma: Okay.
ambuj sharma: Okay, so, because you said that Lama Intex, if you convert to Markdown, then it can better maintain the context, right? Better than maybe Langchain.
Krish Naik: You want to convert, what to Markdown?
ambuj sharma: If you pass through docklink, right? And then we, then we convert, then you chunk…
Krish Naik: I got it. Yes, yes, for your PDF documents. Now, this is actually the best strategy. It means that you take any PDF, you can convert it into a structure, because for LLMs.
Krish Naik: Markdown is the most friendly format.
Krish Naik: Rather than directly passing this thing. So, if you can convert that into an intermediate format, and dockings by default support that. So in that case, I will say that, yes, you will be getting better results. And even for your images, okay, it supports.
Krish Naik: So, through, any… it can be any… like, it can separate out the images from your PDF, if you have those, and those for every image, if you want to create the captions, that you can do via any API call, by using a multimodal.
Krish Naik: Okay, through that, you can generate the captions automatically also.
ambuj sharma: Okay. Then, for chunking, we can use Lama Index, right?
Krish Naik: You can use Llama Index, it's the default. You have to check.
ambuj sharma: proceed.
Krish Naik: really, if you are working with Markdown, I know for these type of documents, recursive character text beta works really, really good.
Krish Naik: So you don't need to worry about it, so I can see it.
ambuj sharma: Okay, so for lockdown, you…
Krish Naik: So, for Matt, don't go ahead, first of all.
ambuj sharma: Okay, so for the one, we use Docklink, or we use Lama Index?
Krish Naik: No, no, no, no.
ambuj sharma: comedy.
Krish Naik: Once you have that intermediary stuff.
Krish Naik: you will be getting the markdown. Then, on top of the markdown, directly using docklinks, you can create the chances.
ambuj sharma: Okay.
Krish Naik: Dockling has that support. Once you have that, output to markdown format, then you can convert them into chunks.
Krish Naik: Okay, so you have… otherwise, if you want a separate chunking operation on top of the markdown, then you can use LangChain. It means that if you use Docklink, less amount of code. Again, for LangChain, again, two to three lines of code that you need to add.
ambuj sharma: Okay, and for retrieval, then again, 19 for retrieval.
Krish Naik: Yes, retrieval, it means that the same retrieval engine, whether you want to go for Lanshan or Llama both, support the same function.
Krish Naik: Okay. And one thing I would suggest, please, if you're working with images, please try to look into some VLMs, which are provided in Docklink. Generally, there is a Granite models, multiple Granite docklink models out there, which are really good for images.
Krish Naik: So that will really help you out.
ambuj sharma: Okay, alright.
ambuj sharma: And, so if you use chonky, suppose, for chunking, then I think we… do we lose the capability that the node parsers gives us, that they create the metadata and all, from the Lama Index? So, we lose those capabilities with ChongKey, isn't it that thing?
Krish Naik: Now, see, chonky is only, basically, to handle your charts.
Krish Naik: For metadata handling, that is different. That is from your mean gen AI framework, whether it's Langchen or through Lama Intex.
Krish Naik: Because if you are parsing the metadata at any point of time, that metadata will be saving it in your vector DB. So, it's basically before the push to vector DB for every chunk that will be handling your metadata.
ambuj sharma: Okay, alright.
Krish Naik: It's not about chunky. Chunky is not related to metadata. Is this part clear?
ambuj sharma: Right, right. Yeah, yeah, it did.
ambuj sharma: And my last question is that if we, suppose we have indexed a document, and we have updated that document again, right? So, do we need to re-index that, right? Then how we delete or maybe update the previous embedding that we have created?
Krish Naik: There are two approaches, C.
Krish Naik: There are two things.
Krish Naik: There are two approaches regarding updates. You need to track in two ways. One way is simply delete the embedding for that entire file.
Krish Naik: Okay, because the file information you'll be having in that metadata. So, exactly what is the file? For example, in a GitHub, there are so many files, but you always maintain the path of that particular file. For example, the file will be within SRC, within test, some files etc. Now, if that file gets updated.
Krish Naik: Now, through a version control system, you can always track
Krish Naik: For example, in GitHub, okay, that what are the changes in that file? So, if it is only at the end part, then it's fine. You can create a separate embedding for that, and you can keep it as a chunk.
Krish Naik: But if you feel that at any point there are mixed changes in multiple places, the best approach is delete the entire embedded for that file and recreate.
ambuj sharma: Okay, alright, thank you.
Krish Naik: The implementation is much easier if you directly delete it, okay, but it always comes with a cost, because it's completely recreating the embeddings, but if you only create chance for the new added com… new added lines.
Krish Naik: In the new data, that is much cheaper. So you can keep those added things just as a chunk also. That is cheaper, but harder to implement.
Krish Naik: Because you need to track those changes to a FIC version controlling system.
Krish Naik: Alright.
Krish Naik: Aruna… shitty… I don't know.
shrey: Hello.
Krish Naik: Yes.
shrey: Yeah, hi. Hi, sir. So, basically, something similar to the last question, I'm also trying to do something similar. I have a BRD, okay, on which certain rules are aware, and I need to extract those rules. But the problem is, inside the BRDs.
shrey: They can be in images, they… they can be, accents as well, which depict, or define the example of that rule.
shrey: So, I was just assuming, which, besides docklings, any other thing that I can use, or which should be the best approach to actually convert that BRD person.
Krish Naik: There is no base accuracy, you have to do experiments. When I've taught you so many things, you have to do the experiments. I never told dockling a mess.
Krish Naik: I feel that more than 70% of the time, Docklin does the job for you.
Krish Naik: So I think that, yes, it's better. Now, the same thing can be used for unstructured also.
Krish Naik: You can use Lama Parse also. Now, it totally depends upon you. You have to do the experiments on top of the data and try to find.
Krish Naik: First of all, in your PRT, what are the type of docs that you have? Try to list them, and try to find that, yes, Doclink, does it support those things? If it supports, do it directly with Docklinks.
shrey: Okay, okay. But, but, so for, for this particular BRD, the, for example, document might work.
shrey: But, in future, if there is a change in BRD or a new PRD comes along.
shrey: Then, probably, the use of Dockling, I mean, unstructured I.O. will, be… will be a better option. So, how…
Krish Naik: In future, if something came which is out of docklink support, let's take the example. Simply, what you will do in the parsing part, you will create a hybrid parser.
Krish Naik: So for that, you have to look exactly which passing technique. We will simply keep that, okay, if this thing simply appears, then probably we might switch to unstructured or Llama pass.
shrey: Okay. Okay. Got it.
Krish Naik: That's why I taught you, you know, 3 different parsers. The idea is that if one fails, switch to the other. It never happens that all three fails.
Krish Naik: It's very, very weird.
shrey: Okay.
shrey: Got it.
shrey: Excellent question.
Krish Naik: Aruna?
Krish Naik: I have asked you to unmute, but no response.
Krish Naik: Okay, Gemba, already taken your question, I'm lowering your hand.
Krish Naik: Any more questions, please let me know in the chat.
Krish Naik: Okay, Arun, now I'm okay, fine.
Krish Naik: All right. So, see, the next few classes will be difficult, I feel, okay, because, the hybrid search, in simple terms, is easy, if I show you from the implementation point of view. But, as we try to, go deeper, the same thing that I have taught today.
Krish Naik: is available in Lanshan also, okay? But the name is a little bit different. Always, you can look into assemble Retrievers in Lanshan, a very similar functionality, just like Query Fusion that we have done today.
Krish Naik: Okay, it means that the implementations are available there. Like, Langchen keeps on updating them, like, who wins the race, but after 3 months, everyone will have a very similar story.
Krish Naik: Okay, so, I will suggest, directly don't start looking into the advanced features, but at least get used to the structure. Quickly, in that way the things will be…
Krish Naik: much more easier. And a little bit about the fundamentals. I have already… I have pulled a few topics. You can look into them, just to get a better understanding. In the next class, I will start with Heidi Prabhavi, the research paper, first of all.
Krish Naik: And then re-ranking, and even, like, few resources, because in the past month of December, really few game-changing
Krish Naik: I can say research paper scheme. I don't know how many of you track papers, but really, so, like, because, see, I cannot read every paper, that is the main problem.
Krish Naik: If I will share them with you, if you guys have time, please go through them. Even re-ranking everybody, teacher, even I'll be teaching you, but again, people are moved to re-ranking free rad also, where really we have proved that re-ranking doesn't work at every point of time. Even I feel, re-ranking is a bottleneck sometimes.
Krish Naik: But many people are using, because it has become a…
Krish Naik: Like, traditional way of doing that.
Krish Naik: The idea is to sometimes go against the tradition, you might get better results.
Krish Naik: Murta, you have placed your hand.
Krish Naik: you have raised your handbags?
Krish Naik: Yes, Nate.
Murtuza Saifee: Can I go ahead? Thanks for the session. Actually, yeah, today's topic was a little bit of advanced. Actually, I got stuck on one of the things initially, was on the IDE, because
Murtuza Saifee: I was thinking that IDE is the part, probably, before we do and insert the, the vectors into the vector store.
Krish Naik: No, no, no.
Murtuza Saifee: But then later on, I got clicked.
Krish Naik: It's only… that's why, even in the notepad I wrote down first, the user query will come. When it will come.
Krish Naik: When we were making a retrieval approach thing.
Murtuza Saifee: So, we don't need to, actually generate anything from our own.
Krish Naik: You don't need to generate nothing. Automatically.
Murtuza Saifee: It's all automated, because.
Krish Naik: To and what?
Murtuza Saifee: I was confused, I was linking it with, you know, the things that we do in evaluation, where we generate some.
Krish Naik: No, no, no, no question.
Murtuza Saifee: So, on that path I was going.
Krish Naik: No, no, no, here it's, that automatic.
Murtuza Saifee: Alright, perfect, thanks. Yeah, this is what I wanted to clarify.
Krish Naik: Thanks, bud.
shrey: So, sorry about that. I had just one more question. Today, in today's class, we discussed around, query expansion, right? .
Krish Naik: Query… I never told query expansion, I only told query transformation.
shrey: Transformation, alright, okay. Yeah, I was just, I was just going through the, the paper of, RAG as a survey that you shared. So, in which, there are three pre-retrieval, right? Query, routing, rewriting, and expansion.
shrey: So, today you explained about query transformation. So, does this cover, all three? I mean, I don't think query routing is covered, but querying and expansion, does this cover?
Krish Naik: No, no, these are different.
Krish Naik: Okay. These are different.
Krish Naik: Query expansion is different, that is, query routing is also different. Routing is a lesser, much more, rather than an application. But, for now, this is a query transformation, in simple terms. Even query expansion, query decomposition, these things also comes under query transformation.
shrey: Okay, so in future, we will be studying, this… these three-retrieval techniques as well.
Krish Naik: Yes, those things will come. Step by step, these are the fundamentals, then I will jump into those things. Decomposition, expansion, those things.
shrey: Alright, okay. So, I mean, if I… if I… I have actually worked on this, simple rag, and I've been able to
shrey: implement that. But, to increase the efficiency, or, or, rather, if I, if I use, I'm not sure the correct terminology, the metrics is accuracy metrics.
shrey: So, which should be the approach, initially? What should be the step-by-step process? Changing the different kind of.
Krish Naik: 15 bucks.
shrey: process, this one.
Krish Naik: No, no, no, no, she…
Krish Naik: Optimization can be done every level. So, generally, it can be done on parsing also.
Krish Naik: Now, really, like, when you are creating the chunks, there are multiple strategies in there. Sometimes we create cushion for every chunk. In that way, it becomes helpful. Whenever the query comes directly, it can look for that particular question.
Krish Naik: Okay, in your chunk, in that way, also, it can increase, sometimes people keep metadata. Now, these strategies are not predefined. You really need to test it out in your use case, whether they fit or not.
Krish Naik: I feel at the first level, always focus on the data level. Later on, if your data level really works good in the initial level, at least for your retrieval, at least I can say the accuracy might increase only by 0.3, 0.2%.
Krish Naik: Okay, because the retrieval level changes, I won't say there will be very, very huge impact. The huge impact always comes in your data.
shrey: Okay.
Krish Naik: how you are creating your jobs, and there are no fixed tools.
Krish Naik: There are more than 30-50 rules. Even, like, every paper has their own different…
Krish Naik: Now, the idea is that you need to do the research for that few examples I have already given, and you need to test it.
Krish Naik: Because it totally depends upon the data when we feel. Sometimes you create the chunks, but in every chunk, whether there is a relevant data, so when you try to fire a query, based on that query, do you think that, will I get this answer or not?
Krish Naik: Then sometimes some manual information addiction on top of the chunk also that I can…
shrey: Okay, okay.
shrey: So, the first approach should always be converting the data.
Krish Naik: I work on data level first. The idea is, if you make better quality chunks with metadata, that is the first purpose.
shrey: Excuse me.
Krish Naik: then move to the other things, whatever thing, re-ranking other things. So, the idea is always start with a simple thing.
Krish Naik: Then, take the next steps.
shrey: Okay, got it.
shrey: Okay, thank you so much.
Krish Naik: on break time.
ambuj sharma: Yes, hello, sweet.
ambuj sharma: My question is that,
ambuj sharma: So, for tracing the data that we use, so for the 9 chain, we have 9Smith.
ambuj sharma: But it's just paid for, it's only… it can be used locally, is it free, but for the…
Krish Naik: Which one? Langchain we have?
ambuj sharma: Langesmith, for tracing the calls and all.
Krish Naik: Yes.
ambuj sharma: So, do we have any free tools, like, available for tracing the calls if you're doing some dry information and you want to check it?
Krish Naik: You can use OPEC.
Krish Naik: O-P-I-K.
Krish Naik: OPEC from Cometamin.
Krish Naik: It's free, open source.
ambuj sharma: Okay, and if you want to connect with the MCPs to get the documents, MCP server, suppose I'm… I want to get the information from Confluence, so, is it possible that… should you use Langdraft for that?
ambuj sharma: Or is it possible to do it with the Llama Index MCP, or something like that, to connect with the config?
Krish Naik: immigrant development.
ambuj sharma: compliment.
Krish Naik: See, whenever we are talking with respect to agents, there I can attach it as an MCP.
Krish Naik: Okay, otherwise, you have to look for the direct API call, because generally, in most of the MSF servers, they do have that HTTP through which you can look in. So you need to find that API. If you're not working agents in your simple use cases, radically try to find that.
ambuj sharma: Okay.
ambuj sharma: And my last question is that, so for the LAMA index, we were, in the retrieval process, we were sending the response using in different modes, like compact or, like, summarize, right? And we normally use the compact for sending the query response back.
Krish Naik: Generally, for…
ambuj sharma: me?
Krish Naik: That is the fastest way to generate the response. Others will take some time, because more characters will be there.
ambuj sharma: Yeah, so in the production, do we send that response directly to the user, or do we use LLM before that and prepare the response?
Krish Naik: We will be sending directly to the user. No, then why again LLM? For generation, you are already using LLM. Then why in the next step, again, you will use LLM?
ambuj sharma: Maybe some system prompt is there, like, like you're used to having LineChain.
ambuj sharma: we used to provide some prompt, right? That helps to, maybe help, to manipulate the response better.
Krish Naik: No, no, no, no, no, no. See, if you want to do manipulation, now the question comes based on the query, every time, if you want a specific structure to be sent to the user. If you have a structure, it means that always the response will be coming in structure, then you need a specific prompt.
Krish Naik: If you don't have a structure which is defined, if you feel that for every response, I cannot define a structure.
Krish Naik: Okay, for example, first of all, like, based on the query, first you say this is your query, then you say, based on the query, like, from what are the different sources, from where you fixed. In that way, if you want to create a structure, then only it is important. Otherwise, templates are not required.
ambuj sharma: Okay, and is it possible to create templates in Nama Index, or…
Krish Naik: Yes, yes, yes, yes, in Llama Index also.
Krish Naik: Everywhere, you can create, like, prompt templates, chat prompt templates directly there.
ambuj sharma: And it would be merged with the compact response, something like that.
Krish Naik: Yeah, generally, now, it totally depends upon you. I feel that compact is much more cheaper at any point of time. If you want to spend, like, 3 summarized, it will give you more response. If you try to go with refined, that will also give you a bit bigger response as compared to Compact.
ambuj sharma: No, so I'm asking that we can add template to the compliance mode as well.
Krish Naik: Generally, before that only I will do it. It means that once I got the output from LLM, after that, again, LLM I don't want. Why? Any times I want to spend money.
Krish Naik: on LLM calls. Probably, my idea would be to make an architecture through a single call only I can handle that.
ambuj sharma: Okay.
ambuj sharma: Perfect, thanks.
Krish Naik: All right, so I think, usually the questions are taken for today.
Krish Naik: Tracking research papers, I tried it through Substack, majorly. Substack is there, alpha signal is there, two things are there.
Krish Naik: Few people I know, like Elrish and other people, are there. Directly, they are there. Few researchers, it's majorly researchers who look into those papers. And even…
Krish Naik: just follow pioneers, they always refer to people much more. That is the fastest way I can say.
Krish Naik: Okay, because, see, now I cannot tell that all these guys I share in one place, okay? Because in Substack also, when I follow, like, more than 30-40 people out there.
Krish Naik: So from there, I know, like, Elvish is one guy. If you want that, okay, probably, like,
Krish Naik: I will copy-paste the name, and you can do that search later on. I will share that in LinkedIn.
Krish Naik: AI Papers Academy in YouTube. I've not gone through YouTube, just through that, but, yes.
Krish Naik: All right, guys, so I think for today we are done. I had one question, Muddha, sir. Raise your hand, Muddha, sir.
Krish Naik: Montessor?
Krish Naik: You can't raise hand, then, if you can't raise hand, then just let me search your name.
Krish Naik: Muntas are allowed to talk. Yes.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, Paul. Well, the orthogonal question here,
Mudassar Hakim: there is slate chunking, right? I had read somewhere about Clara, I've been able to find details about it, and that.
Krish Naik: the laptop.
Mudassar Hakim: Lara.
Mudassar Hakim: And then…
Krish Naik: Lara.
Mudassar Hakim: concept where we are delaying the, I think, encoding or chunking. Do you remember anything of that sort?
Krish Naik: Lara I have not used, so really, like, Lara…
Krish Naik: Let me just search, Lara Chunking.
Mudassar Hakim: I think it was Clara, just a second.
Krish Naik: Lara or Clara?
Mudassar Hakim: Exclad.
Mudassar Hakim: C-L-A-R-A.
Krish Naik: Apple's… Apple releases Clara, a new approach.
Mudassar Hakim: Continuous latent reasoning, yeah, that's the full form of it.
Krish Naik: Okay, no, Apple releases, no, Apple generally…
Krish Naik: Yes, I got it. Their tokenization approach. This I have gone through, but I've never looked into the main implementation of Clara.
Krish Naik: Because whenever Apple releases something directly, I don't feel it's available to do the implementation through Workita.
Krish Naik: Because the GitHub is there, and the paper also, I can see, and they have a model in Hugging Face. If they have a model in Hugging Face, we can do the implementation. And when I'm looking into the implementation.
Krish Naik: The paper has been removed from archive.
Krish Naik: Alright, the paper has been deleted.
Krish Naik: But, I can see here, let me just look into the paper once.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: Alright, Clara, Beijing retrieval and generation using continued latent reasoning, yes.
Krish Naik: do this implementation with respect to GitHub, let me see…
Krish Naik: There is no package that has been released yet. They have simply told they have to… Now, that's the toughest part. Now, to work with this, you need an SFT trainer.
Krish Naik: SFT trainer really means… Again, GPU.
Krish Naik: Deep-seat, flaccine, so many things, see?
Krish Naik: just to try this, I need so many things. Then it's not feasible.
Krish Naik: That's the main thing. So, when you look into the requirement, just look here, deep speed with flash attention is fine, accelerate is fine. For all this, and here, very specifically, when I look into, this is a SFT, supervised fine tuning. So, generally, I feel that cleaning will be done using
Krish Naik: Some type of library, probably TRL.
Krish Naik: TRL is the major library, because this is used widely, so TRL data.
Krish Naik: So, the implementation will be a bit tougher. But at the same thing, we can do the, as you can see, transformers, reinforcement learning. Through this, we do the training. Can you see your deep speed and accelerate?
Krish Naik: The implementation is tough. It's not go-to one. This is right now, based on the research. If you want, we can create an API for this.
Krish Naik: But you have to train on top of your own data. This part, I feel…
Krish Naik: And this is where you have things. Because the scripts are available.
Krish Naik: Let me look, till now, 4 issues have been…
Krish Naik: Does this support macOS module not found, or lost building, okay.
Krish Naik: The community is less around this, although stars I can see, too, it has.
Krish Naik: But, not a proper dog.
Mudassar Hakim: This actually came up when I was looking up for late chunking. So, Clara came up as a latent encoder.
Mudassar Hakim: And it kind of delays to get the entire data. And it's more so for production system.
Krish Naik: Hmm, that it's… when you say suitable.
Krish Naik: So, you say suitable, but do you think…
Krish Naik: From the implementation point of view, it is…
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah.
Krish Naik: That's why. Yeah. Compressor, it's telling all right, it has a compressor and a generator. A query reason, okay, here you can see the cosine similarity task is here, based on that.
Krish Naik: Now, this compressed docs, where they are saving, that's probably a vector DB here. Now, this is the continuous tokens.
Krish Naik: backward, because I can see the… it will be cheaper at the end of the day, because here it has a training stage, it means always you have to do the training.
Krish Naik: Now, this is one tough part for anybody, because for this, probably I need a GPU instance continuously running. The main problem of this training stage, when you feel that you have set up documents which are fixed, you know that for the next 10 months, it won't be coming.
Krish Naik: If you feel that every day or every hour one document is coming, this type of system doesn't become scalable.
Krish Naik: It means that you need to have a training machine on continuously, 24 hours, just to perform the training. If you do the training, then only you will be able to do the inference.
Krish Naik: I hope you got my point. So, like, your infrastructure cost really increases.
Mudassar Hakim: Hmm.
Mudassar Hakim: No, I agree.
Krish Naik: Because I feel that that is the only con, I feel, because if you have a training stage included.
Krish Naik: There are, good models also, just because of infrastructural cost, I can't do the implementation.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay.
Krish Naik: This implementation, we can replicate it, it's not like that ML Cloud. I will take that, okay, I'm probably using a GPU, at least. Let me take a clone and let me see.
Krish Naik: Whether it is possible or not.
Mudassar Hakim: To do the implementation.
Krish Naik: probably… I need a serverless GPU, I will take the serverless GPU, and I will do that.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, and another orthogonal part was, the way we have Heidi, right, with respect to the retrieval part. I think there is something called as query expansion and multi-query ran.
Krish Naik: Yes, yes, yes. Those are query transformations only. Step by step, we'll be coming to that later.
Mudassar Hakim: We'll go back into that, right? Yeah, that's what I wanted to look at for challenging, I think.
Krish Naik: This will be doing it. Once we start Haystack, in Haystack, everything is there. You will understand. Just a simple function pulls up.
Krish Naik: Because the learning curve is the easiest in his stack, but the most highest level of abstraction.
Krish Naik: the highest level of abstraction in their NASA. It means that they're nothing. It's just two lines, everything is done. Your ID, your query transformation, everything in one shot.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, cool, cool. Yep, thanks, thanks, Paul. That's what I have.
Krish Naik: Okay, alright. So I think, guys, Pradhan, do you have any project on this week? Yesterday, I've given you the implementation of Late Changa, tried to do it from your site, a few people have done it and shared.
Krish Naik: That's for now, nothing more. Okay, the idea is just go through the fundamentals of NLP, the topics, if you don't know further about it.
Krish Naik: Alright guys, so let's conclude the session for today. Let's meet next week.
Krish Naik: And, please go through the content, and, wherever you feel, if you have something, add print statements, then also you could not understand, then talk me.
Krish Naik: Wherever we want.